You're tuned to the drive on your 247
home of the black and gold Steelers
Nation Radio.
Good afternoon, Steeler Nation, and
welcome to a special edition of the
drive here in fabulous Phoenix, Arizona
at the Builtmore for the 2026 NFL League
meetings. Wesler, Matt Williamson on
location here, cross country on a
special Sunday show. What's going on,
Matt? I'm I'm excited for these next
couple days.
>> Yeah, you should be. It's a pretty cool
event. It's much different than things
like the combine that we've done
recently. Um, we haven't been to Arizona
for there's two years in between. I
don't know exactly why this happened,
but usually the way it was explained to
me way back when by Dale and company was
they do one on the west coast, Arizona,
then they do one on the east coast,
Florida.
>> That's what I always thought.
>> And then they go back and forth, back
and forth. And for whatever reason,
there have been the last two were in
Miami. So, we haven't been here for a
while, but I think this was the first
one I came to. So, I'll be going to this
my fourth or fifth in a row.
>> And it's just a different vibe. I mean
again it's not coaches and scouts and a
lot of draft nicks or things like that.
It's not as much hustle bustle. It's in
a very nice location. It's gorgeous
here.
>> Yeah. I mean golf courses everywhere and
obviously a lot of money and things like
that. And
>> this is where a lot
>> not to mention a lot of sunshine
out here too that we already but this is
where a lot of big decisions are made.
you know, a lot of it behind the walls,
so we're not privy to the conversations,
but we're hanging with, you know,
rubbing elbows with these folks. You
know, it's cool.
>> Yes, we are. It is. It's a It's my first
time here, which I'm excited for. As you
mentioned, it's just kind of a different
vibe from what we typically do. We will
have some guests and everything. Today's
kind of setup day, though. It's just us
and the New York Jets in here right now.
>> If you could turn these cameras around,
there's just a lot of people setting up
everywhere. Like right in front of us is
a ballroom that there's going to be all
16 NFC coaches will sit there and have a
breakfast tomorrow. The day after all 16
AFC coaches are in there. Right behind
us is like a I think they they set this
up for like brunches and things like
that behind us. But everybody's just
kind of getting ready for the big stuff
to happen. But I have seen a head coach
already and you know
>> Yes, we did. Mike Mike Vreyel walked
right past us.
>> Oh, really? I saw Dan Quinn.
>> Did you see Dan Quinn? Yeah, Vel was
walking past us just a few minutes ago.
Um, so yeah, today,
>> so they're staying in the building we're
at.
>> Correct. Right. Correct. Yeah. Today
kind of the uh the setup day, the the
the kind of first um moving and shaking
here around the Builtmore. Uh and then
tomorrow is when it really gets going.
Tomorrow, as you mentioned, the NFC head
coaches will speak. Mike McCarthy will
speak to the Pittsburgh media tomorrow
and then do his his national media stuff
on Tuesday. Also, Omar Khan and Mr.
Rooney speaking on Tuesday. So, we will
have um
>> all the top people in every organization
are pretty much
>> Exactly.
>> available in some way, shape, or form,
including the commissioner of the league
>> and and absolutely Roger Goodell will
speak here, too, and and Matt will have
a fun dinner here tomorrow night, the
owners dinner, which I'm which I'm
looking forward to. Brought my uh my
finest duds for the for the big fancy
dinner tomorrow night. Uh but yeah, so
today is kind of a set the scene day a
little bit, if you will. And with that,
>> I would imagine some owners and GMs and
coaches are still flying in today. I I I
don't We got in last night.
>> Yes. It's probably a mix of both, I
would.
>> I would think. I would think.
>> We had an outstanding Mexican meal last
night as well, too, by the way.
>> Yeah. A little bit of a long flight and
we were all starving. Hit the Mexican
and margaritas pretty hard. It was
great.
>> Had one had one of the best one of the
best burritos I've had in a long long
time here in uh in beautiful Phoenix,
Arizona. So, Matt, uh we'll just kind of
start with a maybe a little 411, little
primer here, okay, of uh of all the
moving and shaking, what to expect over
the next couple days, the different
topics that will be on the agenda.
Right. So, this is all about voting on
rules, bylaws, resolution, proposals,
um, you know, all those
>> a lot of discussions behind the scenes,
too. By the way, folks, it probably goes
without saying, but it's not like
>> the combine you'll hear. I mean, I'm
sure there's things like, you know, can
we sign this guy or let's talk trades or
blah blah blah. I I wonder what they're
like here. But you will walk around here
and I'm I don't think I'm revealing too
much, but if you spend enough time on
this property, you'll see two owners in
the corner just kind of what wonder what
they're chatting about or two GMs in the
corner and maybe because they were on a
staff together 20 years ago and they're
good buddies.
>> They're talking about their wives and
their kids and how's everyone
>> tons of that. But it also might be like
hm thinking about trading Miles Garrett,
you know,
>> about you hearing about AJ Brown.
>> Right. Right. Right. Right. I mean,
there's all the people that make
decisions are here. So,
>> yes. And so, it is a real um kind of all
the power players of the National
Football League
>> and we're just kind of fly on the wall,
you know.
>> Exactly. Right. And so, here's some of
the different proposals, some of the
different things that we could expect to
be on the agenda this week. Um, we
discussed some of this last week, but I
think it's just a good refresher here on
this on this Sunday as we get started.
>> Bonus drive, by the way.
>> Bonus threeh hour edition of the drive
here today, Monday, and Tuesday. three
days
>> and then we're traveling Wednesday.
>> And then we travel on Wednesday. Yep. Um
the kicking team able to declare an
onside kick at any time during the game.
Of course, now for those who are
unfamiliar, you can only do that in the
fourth quarter, right? We all know, I
think most people know by now that you
have to declare the onside kick, but
that's only allowed in the fourth
quarter. I have to think, Matt, though,
that they'll change this and you can
declare an on-side kick at any time
during the game. I remember when the
original uh rule was passed about it and
then there was that caveat about only in
the fourth quarter and I think I was on
with Dale and we're like why only in the
fourth quarter? You know what if I want
to do it to start the game and it might
not be smart. I mean the recovery rate
isn't very good now because you have to
tell people it's coming. There's no
surprise on side to start the half in
the Super Bowl so to speak. You know
what I mean? And that's one that's the
only thing I don't like about the new
kickoff rule in general is there's just
no way around it because you have to
have a different formation if people
haven't thought this through. So you
have to at least declare that we're
going to line up differently and thus
kick an onside kick and then everyone
knows it's coming. But why do you have
to wait till the fourth quarter? Like
I'll be shocked if that gets any
resistance among I mean it seemed like
this kind of they should have got right
the first time honestly. Why even put
that in there?
>> Agreed. Completely agree. So that's uh
that's number one in terms of the
playing rules proposals that will be on
the agenda. Number two uh is eliminating
teams kicking teams incentive to
intentionally kick the ball out of
bounds when kicking off from the 50 yard
line. So basically
>> if there is a
>> this was just a pure loophole.
>> This is a pure loophole. We saw Danny
Smith last year. You know, if there's a
if there's a penalty on the if there's a
penalty on the receiving team and so you
get to kick off from the 50 yard line,
it just behooves you to boot that thing
out of bounds because you're going to be
surrendering less yardage basically.
>> And no one's going to take it to the
house on you or there's no risk. You
know exactly what you're getting. And I
think that was just an overlooked
loophole because we talked about this
the other day. You know, like I I
vividly remember being here or at a
owners meeting when all they could talk
about is the dynamic kickoff. The
dynamic kickoff.
>> It was a huge story two years ago.
>> Huge story. And it was up until all
through the preseason and training camp
and are they going to have to spend half
of their practice working on the dynamic
kickoff? Of course, we're exaggerating.
They didn't. But I mean, how are these
teams going to handle it? Are they going
to start, you know, Danny had to watch
all this different preseason tape of all
the different teams, how they handled
it? And in some ways it ended up being
kind of much a do about nothing in year
one. It didn't change things
drastically.
>> The scuttlebutt was much greater than
the impact.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I I got a kick out of it
too cuz I remember being here and they
basically I mean I'm again exaggerating.
They come out of these doors and they're
like the dynamic kickoff passed and then
like 4 seconds later on my phone it's
like the Steelers signed Cordurell
Patterson who's like the best kickoff
returner ever. I'm like, I bet that's
not a coincidence, you know, and
it was fine, but year one, it was kind
of much to do about nothing. I think you
were right.
>> Last year we saw more.
>> Last year it really made a ton of
impact. And the Steelers or the league
do they do want more scoring, but we've
talked about this a ton like average
starting field position went up
drastically just last year. And oh, by
the way, the kickers are getting so much
better. You you're in field goal range
after a first down or two. two first
downs and if you got the right kicker,
you're absolutely already in field goal
range.
>> That's a lot different than it was four
or five years ago.
>> It sure is. It sure is. And then last
one. So, a lot of these proposals,
>> but they didn't catch this loophole. I I
kind of went off on a tangent. Correct.
Yeah. When they because it's so new. I
mean, there's not that many kickoffs
that would even apply to this.
>> And you give these special teams
coordinators um the opportunity to
figure something like that out and
they're going to.
>> It only takes one and then the whole
league knows, right?
>> Exactly. Right. Then it's on tape then
everyone knows and goes, "Oh yeah, let's
do that, too.
>> Kick it out of bounds." Right. Um,
>> and the Steelers did it. Boswell did it.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. And we were all like,
"That's a great call. That's a great
decision." Offense five yards extra
back.
>> A couple people were like, "Oh, come on,
Bos. What are you doing?" Like, "No,
that was on purpose. That was smart."
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Uh, third one here, and this is the last
one that affects directly the kickoffs.
Uh, we all know that there are alignment
requirements for the receiving team in
terms of the setup zone. They want to
modify some of the parameters around
those alignments. I think they give
teams more flexibility.
>> Yeah. And and this is something I don't
know the exact parameters of, but I
think you're only allowed to align in
one formation.
>> I believe you are correct.
>> Which again, I mean, you can't tell the
offense you have to align in 12
personnel with these guys. When you
think about where else do we do that,
>> right? Right. I mean, special teams
coaches need to be creative, too. And
>> you have rules only this guy, this many
guys have to be on the line of
scrimmage, all those different things,
but you still have wiggle room freedom
within those confines.
>> So, like example, you know, bring it
back to the Steelers. I mean, they
always had basically Warren and Gainwell
as their two deep guys. But I always
thought that was goofy. And I even
commented at the time, I'm like, if you
do have Corduro Patterson in his prime,
I want him back there alone with
somebody else blocker. Right. Exactly.
Because not to mention, every kicker is
not going to kick it to Patterson.
They're going to kick it to the other
guy. And I'm sure you could be like, you
know, come get it anyway. But, you know,
but still, I don't want to put two guys
back there because I paid this dude a
ton to take every kickoff. Exactly.
Right. You know what I mean?
>> Exactly right. Let's Let's make it a
strength.
>> Yeah. And and I don't know what the
other parameters are, the up guys and
the middle guys and that I just don't
know enough about the special teams of
it all, but why not be as creative as
possible?
>> It makes a ton of sense.
>> And punt formations, you can be in
however you want. You can have a bunch
of wide guys, you can have tight, you
can
>> Exactly. Right. Yeah. You could you
could go for a punt block and back cover
and Yeah.
>> You know, they're not saying you have to
align this way.
>> So, those are the three related to
kickoff specifically. Um, all proposed
by the competition.
>> Probably all pass, don't you think? Off
the top of your head.
>> I would think off the top of my head, I
guess. So
>> maybe I'm missing a negative to but they
maybe they just it's year three of this
or year four of this and we found
loopholes. Let's fix them.
>> I I think that makes a ton of sense.
Next one and this one will be very this
is maybe the the most intriguing one to
me. Also proposed by the competition
committee allowing league personnel to
consult with the onfield officials when
considering disqualifications for
flagrant football acts and non-foot acts
that are not called on the field. So
things like punches, spitting, stomping
on, unsportsmanlike conduct that the
referees miss, think Jaylen Ramsay verse
Jamar Chase last year, that spitting
incident.
>> League personnel, you know, from the
booth or from the league offices or
whatever the case may be, would have the
ability to buzz down to the officials
and say, "Hey, that guy just spit on
that guy or that guy just stomped on
that guy's leg in the pile." Um, non
football flagrant football acts. So,
I've been giving this a little more
thought, and
I'm sure every owner and everyone in
charge of this great league does not
want that look. You know, here's a
replay 500 times in a row of someone
spitting in the other one.
>> With with Jaylen Carter and Dak Prescott
in the
>> Right. Right. Right. It's a terrible
look. And I'm sure they want all that
stuff out. Good. I mean on the surface
everyone all these rules are going to
sound good today you know but if you
start breaking them down I immediately
start thinking like well how far are we
going to take this if it's like the
whistle blows and I'm walking away and I
give you one of these I don't know let's
look at it you know like how how far are
we going to take this
>> for those listening on radio Matt just
gave me a light push you know like I
mean like he's under there giving them
the business I'm like some of this
stuff's just boys being boys and
football yeah let's not take it too far.
I mean, gross frag flag f flagrant
things, you know, punch below the belt
or, you know, but not even like
>> someone's ankle,
>> not even like a shot to the face
afterward. I mean, like these things
have happened since the dawn of time.
Let's not relegate everything out of it.
It's my only worry there.
>> That's a very good point by you because
through that you'd be leaving a lot of
interpretation to the official,
>> right? Like, well, why didn't we look at
that?
>> Because you might think that that's
flagrant. I might not. Yeah,
>> I might just think that's part of the
game
>> and it might be worth a flag if it had
been caught the first time around. But
do we have to watch all of them? You
know, again, I mean, I'm sure it's just
the big ones. Monday Night Football,
someone spitting each other face or
doing something, right? You can't have
that. I get it.
>> No, that's a great point by you, though,
because that does leave a lot of
interpretation down to the official and
what they would consider flagrant and
non- football acts.
>> And then finally, last one.
>> Lastly, I mean, I wonder also like a
obscene gesture or a throat slash or any
of those type of things, you know, maybe
grabbing yourself or something like
that. that count
>> a certain finger on the hand might be in
the middle might be in the middle of
your fist.
>> Right. Right.
>> That's that's again that's that's all
the stuff they'll be discussing I'm
sure. And what exactly can the
parameters of this be? How far can we
take it? And is it realistically
enforceable? Are we putting these
referees in a tough spot
>> because I don't even know know those
things need to be under review.
>> True.
>> Under the review for maybe giving the
guy the finger, you know, like
>> Yeah, I I think you're right. like a
spit or like a a crotch punch or a stamp
on somebody that's different. But there
is a fine line between just that guy's
being a jerk
>> verse something that needs punished.
>> Yeah. I mean I remember like Nomicon Sue
back in the day would get up after a
sack or hitting the quarterback and like
stomp on his hand. Like we don't need
that.
>> We don't need that.
>> Frankly, Joe Green did a lot of these
things too and you know the Steelers
aren't
>> Jack Lambert baby.
>> Right. Yeah. Yeah. Last one uh proposed
by the competition committee of the five
potential uh rules uh proposals is for
one year only allow the NFL officiating
department to correct clear and obvious
misses made by onfield officials that
impact the game. However, with the
caveat of this is only in the event that
there is a work stoppage involving the
game officials represented by the NFL
referees association. For those who are
like what the heck is Wes talking about?
>> Yeah, there's a lot of words there. The
league and the NFL referees association
are currently at a little bit of a
stalemate.
>> So they do not have a contract
contractually. The NFL official
officials do not have their It's the
same thing as we see when there's a CBA
between the the league and the players.
There's also that same thing between the
league and the referees association.
>> There could be a striker or work short
or out
>> like we had in 2012. Everybody remembers
the replacement refs. There is potential
for that again this year. And if that
was the case, we wouldn't have the fail
Mary type situation again like we had in
Seattle in 2012 between the Seahawks and
the Packers where one referee signaling
touchdown, the other signaling
incomplete and they have to argue about
it for 10 minutes. This would give them
>> which frankly could have happened with
the the real ref, but it's just a
terrible look. It's like, oh, they're
replacing refs and right.
>> This gives me worry, Matt. This gives me
pause. one that they are
doing this preemptively because they're
thinking that there's going to be a a
referee strike
>> and two that they realize that it's
probably not going to be the highest
level of officiating.
>> I don't know, maybe I'm looking into it
too far, but this one is kind of putting
making my spidey senses tingle.
>> Yeah. Part of me also thought maybe it's
a really good negotiating ploy for the
refs. like we're preparing for life
without you guys,
>> you know, so maybe we're going to offer
you 10% less than you're asking or who
knows.
>> I I mentioned this the other day.
>> I also think refs are a little bit like
drivers, you know, like you get to an
age where you might have to take your
driver's test again. It's a great like
I'm not saying having quote scab or
replacement refs would be good for the
league, but you might find three or four
that are better than the dudes that are
getting paid fulltime for it. You know,
>> it might be it might be much worse, too.
You know,
>> you know, it's going to be scrutinized
more under Min, which is already
scrutinized a lot.
>> Yes. Exactly. Right. So, those are the
rules proposals on the agenda here over
the next couple days. There's also
>> I will say compared to other years this
is a little light little light you know
like the kickoff rule or tush push or
like people have been talking about for
months like they can't wait till this
then they battle it out and it's 49 to
51 or whatever you know.
>> Yes,
>> these seem a little bit reserved.
>> Yes, there are some bylaw proposals too.
We'll discuss those when we return.
We'll kind of continue our
>> I'm sure they'll be talking about 18
game. I mean there'll be those kind of
talks going on here.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. We'll continue
with kind of the uh the owners meeting
411, the primer, the need to know here
as we are just getting started from the
Builtmore in Arizona, beautiful Phoenix
for the 2026 NFL annual league meeting.
Joining us now is a a name and a voice
uh that you're all familiar with if you
are regular listeners to SNR and to the
drive. It's our buddy Chris Hack of DK
Pittsburgh Sports. Chris, what's up,
man? Thanks for taking the time. And got
to imagine you're enjoying this sunshine
a little bit just like we are. uh to the
point where I I've like tried to not but
like bothered my wife a little bit who
does not like the cold weather, likes
the hot weather, born and raised in
Texas and everything. And so she sees
she's like, "What's the weather going to
be?" Like, "What do you think the
weather's going to be?" She's just then
I got some really angry texts and
everything.
>> I was going to say you two are a little
younger than me. You're you're you're
hasn't been married as long. You haven't
been fathers as long and whatnot.
Really? You're longer than I thought.
But I've learned quickly like don't take
pictures of the dinner that the Steelers
bought you that's like surf and turf or
send it home when they're eating like
stums or don't send you know the weather
here couldn't be better blah blah blah
like nobody's happy for you back home.
>> It's very true. So you're saying the the
picture of the sunshine and the palm
tree that I sent my wife this morning
that one might get me the doghouse when
we get back on Wednesday. Chances are
she's not like, "Oh, I'm so happy Wes is
having a great time right while I'm here
with the two kids."
>> Uh Chris, let's get into it, man. Plenty
that we want to discuss with you. Um a
lot of different rule proposals, bylaw
proposals. That's kind of the meat and
potatoes of what's going on here the
next few days. What stands out to you?
What do you think is the most intriguing
thing on the docket?
>> It sounds kind of boring to me, but it
maybe it's just because I like pra the
practicality of it. Um, right now the
way things are, uh, when when somebody
gets placed on IR before the season,
they have to miss four games and you're
not allowed to return them to practice
until after those four games are gone.
There's a proposal on the table to allow
that player to have their 21-day window
opened uh, after I think the first game
so that they could then practice.
>> We didn't touch on that one.
>> While still uh, going through those four
games that they have to miss.
>> Interesting. And that way if they are
going to miss those four games, they've
already been practicing and then they
can make that decision. Hey, okay,
they're at the end of their 21-day
window. We're going to go ahead and
activate them and then they can play in
the next game. So it's not like four
games.
>> So what how does it sit now? I'm a
little confused.
>> Well, because right now it's four games
no matter what.
>> Like when you got hurt,
>> you can't go to back to practice or
anything. You're you're out for four
games.
>> Obviously, when guys then first get back
on on the practice field, they're not
just immediately going to they're
recovering from an injury.
So there there's a ramp up that has to
happen which is why there's a 21day
window. So like in theory they're out
for a minimum of four games but they
really might miss six or seven. So this
way, especially if it's an injury where
you're like, "Hey, we know we're not
going to have him for the first four
games, but there's a really good chance
that we can have him back for game for
for week five or our fifth game and then
he can do three whole weeks of
practicing in that process right now of
being out for those four games. That's
not the way it is right now." Okay.
>> So that to me,
>> the way you proposed, it seems like
that's an obvious yes.
>> That's what I would think.
The practicality of it makes so much
sense. not like. So that's why like it's
not one of the one of the like grabbier
rule or bylaw proposals or anything like
that, but it's the one that intrigued me
because I'm like, dude, why isn't it
like this already?
>> Yeah. So, why did it take this long?
Yeah. What's the downside to that?
>> That one's That one kind of stood out to
me. There was a few other ones, but that
one kind of stood out to me.
>> Okay. Are you in favor or not of being
able to trade draft picks five years in
advance?
>> I'm not really a fan of it.
>> We didn't like it at all either.
>> Not a fan of it. We didn't like it. It
it I worry that it would get too NBAish
where you would get halfway through the
season and and a third 40% of your
league would already clearly be be
punting on the future
>> and just watching the lesser product
from a lot of
>> I don't I don't I I no I don't like it.
I think three years out is is a pretty I
think that's about as far as it should
go.
>> So no, I'm not I'm not a fan of that at
all. Um I'm trying to think like I'm I'm
my mind's blanking on some of the other
ones, but yeah, that was a that was
another one that's kind of fun. uh the
Steelers proposal of uh you know making
what the thing last year permanent.
>> Explain the behind the scenes and kind
of the logistics of that to
>> what do you know about that one?
>> So the negotiating window is is is funny
because it's like it opens and like
teams can then talk with
uh players agents but this way you get
more access to the player and
>> that's kind of what we thought.
>> Yeah. You get more access.
So like and then that
again it's what they did last year or
it's what they've done like this year
because of what was what was passed last
year and so but it was just on a
one-year trial basis and so now they
want to make it permanent. I again with
the fact that it was voted in and I
don't I haven't heard anything about
like this went terribly. This is like so
I would think that's another slam dunk.
Uh but you know we'll see whenever uh
the owners get together and you know
vote on it. But uh I think that's a
another one that's pretty interesting.
>> I couldn't figure out if five was a big
number or a little number though that
the series presented you could do with
five different players.
>> I think so. I I mean
>> maybe it's a good place to start and go
from there. Next year we might be
talking about oh let's bump it to eight,
you know, whatever.
>> Yeah. And then you can always you can
always adjust. I think that's what like
like the whole point of these like bylaw
proposals and and rule proposals is
sometimes okay yeah you start it off on
a trial basis uh and then okay if the
trial goes well okay then let's vote to
make it a permanent rule but then that
rule can continue to be amended okay
that's too many players let's pull it
back or hey we still don't have access
to enough players so let's let's bump it
to seven or you know whatever it is the
next time so I think that's why like
these meetings while like
>> they don't grab a lot of headlines
unless there's something like the tush
push being talked about which is not
being this year and there is quite a bit
on the dynamic kickoff this year too. So
um yeah like
>> these meetings are productive for sure
and and definitely helps shape the
future of the game.
>> Oh definitely.
>> Chris Alec with us here on the drive.
Chris, what are you hearing about um
Matt and I were having some
conversations starting to get a little
worried that we're going to have a
replacement referees situation and some
of the chaos that ensued in 2012. A
repeat of that here. What are what are
you hearing on that front? Do you share
our concerns?
>> There's definitely concern whenever the
two sides aren't talking. There's always
concern about that. Um for for those
like those who are baseball fans, you
know, you know, I mean,
>> lockout, you start, you know,
>> it's it's almost an inevitability at
this point because the two sides aren't
talking. There's like and just and then
you go to this with between the the
league and and and the referees and if
they're not talking, that's never a good
sign.
But what else are you going to do? Like,
you know, this is part of what
negotiating is. And sometimes, you know,
you know, certain sides will do certain
things to to
>> get what they want out of it. And right
now, it's going to be who's going to
blink first. Uh the the good thing from
the referees perspective is they saw
like everybody saw how poor they went
last time. The referees didn't forget
that and fans haven't forgotten that.
It's been almost 15 years, but I think
we all remember it vividly.
>> We've and and there's going to be, you
know, potentially if he resigns, there's
going to be one member of the Steelers,
uh, if Aaron Rogers does come back, uh,
who will remember that front and center.
That's right.
So, uh, yeah, he will, uh,
>> that will be something fun to talk about
if it gets to that. Hopefully, it
doesn't, but when the two sides aren't
talking, that's that's never fun.
>> So, speaking of Rogers, kind of a
two-part question here.
>> Yeah. If he decides he doesn't want to
play football or doesn't want to play
for the Steelers again, do you think
they pivot to a Cousins or a car type
move?
>> Not as a starter, not as a not as an
unquestioned the day you sign the
contract, you're automatically QB1. I
don't
>> you think they that you think Okay.
Well, what do you think would happen? Do
you think they would even go down either
one of those type of roads?
>> What I would think is they would try to
bring in a veteran to go along with what
they have
>> a name like that. Yes. Okay. that's had
start a game
>> and then it would be something along the
lines of okay, you have that veteran
signing, you have Mason Rudolph, you
have Will Howard, and potentially you
also have another quarterback that's
drafted.
>> That's my two-part question, too, is do
you think they draft a mid-round guy?
>> Yes. I I I would lean toward them taking
a quarterback in this class, Rogers or
not?
>> That's that's what I that's what I am
leaning toward right now based off
>> I've really been on the fence about
this. Yeah. Not on what I've heard of
just what I would do. But if Rogers is
not part of the equation, I think he
will be. But if he's not, I think what
you'll have by the time training camp
opens in LRO, you'll have a legitimate
quarterback competition going on.
>> That's what I think you'll you'll you'll
see. I don't think anybody's going to be
>> threeperson quarterback competition.
>> Could be four really. I mean, because
you'll bring in four quarterbacks.
>> Um, now I would think that whoever would
be drafted, whether it be Tai Simpson,
maybe if it's Tai Simpson, you draft him
in the first round, he'd get a good
look. Um, but if it's more of a
mid-round guy, if it's Garrett Nusmire,
Drew Aller, like that like Cole Payton,
like that that type of guy, no, I don't
think he's going to be front and center
to be the starter right away.
>> Uh, but he you give him a look, you give
him a chance, you know? Uh, I think Will
Howard would get a chance, Mason Rudolph
having the experience he has, and then
obviously if you bring in somebody else
like a Kurt Cousins or something like
they'll they'll come in and they'll have
a chance to compete. Um, and they'll
probably have the leg up, but I don't
think anything is guaranteed at that
point.
>> So, along those lines, Rogers, Carr,
Cousins, whoever. Let's say there's an
old guy
>> and there's a new guy, a third round
pick, you know, Nusmeire or, you know, I
like Cole Payton, whatever.
>> Howard's going to make the team.
>> Yep.
>> That seems to me Rudolph would be the
guy that's on the outside looking in.
>> I would think so.
>> Yeah. And maybe you flip him for a
seventh round pick or something.
>> Maybe. Yeah. I mean, because you're not
keeping four quarterbacks. You're not
the Cleveland Browns.
>> Um, so you're you're you're you're
keeping
you you're keeping three quarterbacks
and if it has to be, I think, and and
really when you're talking about the
future of the quarterback position with
this franchise,
>> you don't have that guy to go get in the
first round this year. Like, you have
all this draft capital. You'd love to be
able to go trade up and go get a guy.
Well, that guy doesn't exist. Sure. So,
what you have to do is for this year,
you still have to try to find something
for the future. That means dedicating uh
resources to developing Will Howard.
That means possibly also drafting a
quarterback and not just drafting him in
the third or fourth round, whatever it
is, and then just cutting him. Unless
unless unless he just goes to training
camp and it just bombs. Yes. Like
absolutely terrible. Be like, gosh, this
is already bad rap.
>> Um I don't think that would happen.
>> But that's not the plan when you pick
him in the third round. It's going to
stink. It's not. So, you could
realistically and and from from a Will
Howard perspective, it almost makes
sense for him to go from, okay, he was
he had his red shirt year as a as a
rookie, you know, I mean, he was active
one game when Mason Rudolph was a
starter in Chicago, didn't play any
snaps, obviously.
>> Okay. Well, then now this time, if you
want to take a step forward now, maybe
he ends up being the actual backup. Like
if if Aaron Rogers does come back and
>> I'm hoping Howard by cut down day is a
solid two.
>> That's what you would hope and that's
what
>> I don't think that's asking too much. No
best case scenario.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And so then you have Okay.
Then at that at that point your third
could be a if you draft a guy would be
that guy who would then be what Will
Howard was last year.
>> He's you know if you know everybody's
healthy he's never active. He's the
emergency quarterback. Yeah. Uh maybe
he's active for a game or two as the
backup, you know, if Rogers is
>> or even he's a Cole Payeyton and you
have a Taesm Hill package for him or
something like that weird like that.
Yeah.
>> But then you'd have to activate them.
You'd have to have three active
quarterbacks that day. But
>> yeah, I think when you're talking about
the future of the quarterback position,
you have to start dedicating resources
to developing. And I think the fact that
Mike McCarthy is now the head coach,
you're in a better position to do that
than you were in the past. Okay,
>> few more minutes here with Chris Hack on
the drive. Chris, uh, we were kind of in
the first hour kicking around, um,
things that, you know, other than rules,
proposals, and specific, you know,
bylaws, things like that that could be
discussed by Mike McCarthy, by Omar
Khan. Do you expect any type of clarity
on Brick Jones potentially this week?
Are we going to just have to wait and
see in the summertime on on his health
and status?
>> I don't think we're we're going to get
anything solid on that this week.
>> I'm sure people ask though. Oh, he'll
he'll be I mean McCarthy will be asked
about it. Omar will be asked about it.
Uh because McCarthy will will talk with
Pittsburgh reporters tomorrow. Uh Omar I
think Tuesday. Yes.
>> So
both guys are going to get questions
about Brick. I don't think we're going
to get any clarity. And the thing and
the reason why isn't necessarily because
they they're trying to keep things under
wraps or anything like that. This is
just such a a un It's an unpredictable
injury. I mean, Asante Samuel Jr. had
his own fusion thing.
>> He's able to come back and play, but
then I remember Ryan Watts.
>> Yeah.
>> Final game of the Detroit, you know,
preseason when he was drafted, he, you
know, has that stinger near the end of
the game in that preseason finale in
Detroit. He retired. Yeah.
>> Like it just
>> this has ended careers.
>> It has. And and that's why when you when
you think about this and you think about
from the Steelers perspective on this,
like they don't want to just discard
him. Like he was a first round pick,
>> still young.
>> Yeah, he's still young. You have a fifth
year option decision to make and with
like they have to know like they have to
know if they're going to pay him that
kind of money for for the fifth year
option.
>> So if they
>> I can't imagine they pick up fifth year.
I don't know how you don't. Yeah, I
would lean toward not picking it up
right now. I his level of play was a lot
higher and this injuries out there then
I think it becomes more of a debate.
>> I I would think so too.
>> Cook didn't exist.
>> But even but even if let's just say
Brick like was playing at like a really
high level like there weren't like the
bumps and bruises that he's dealt with
and the ups and downs that he's dealt
with
that kind of an injury that could
possibly be a career ender. You're then
like literally handcuffing yourself
because that that's a that's a yeah it's
a guaranteed money. It's a full cap hit.
It's what 20 million something like
around that. It's it's it's
>> big.
>> That's a that's a big chunk.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> I think the answer is no.
>> I don't think I don't think they do. And
I don't
>> May 1st is the deadline, by the way.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, it's about a month.
>> There's a little bit of time, but I I
don't think that they're going to end up
uh picking that up that picking up that
option just because I don't think
they're going to know. I really like
again I don't think this is a situation
where they know what's going on with
him. They're keeping up. They are still
trying to figure this out and then he's
still recovering. He's still going
through and they're probably talking
with him and going through this entire
process with them and they just don't
know.
>> Got to wait and see.
>> Yeah. And that's that's a really
unfortunate situation to be in for all
all parties involved.
>> So therefore, and other reasons, I look
at left side of the O line as probably
the second biggest need. I don't know if
we've even have to rank them. And I
would not object at all to taking a
first and third round offensive lineman
or a second and fourth round offensive
lineman. I don't think taking two is
crazy. Um and I don't think a first
round offensive lineman is crazy.
>> Yeah, I I could see it happening. I
think the the way the first round goes,
I don't think Vega from Penn State will
be there at 21. if he's still there
somehow at like 16 or 17. I would think
long and hard about trying to trade up
to get him.
>> He's that type of a player. Like like
I'm not gonna like put this kind of like
expectation on him or anything like
that. But the first person I think of
when it comes to Vega is David Dcastro
in terms of what he could provide
possibly. He could be a stable force uh
in the on the interior of the line for a
decade. Like that that that's what you
would draft him to be. He's talented
enough to do it. He's athletic enough to
do it. Um he's a very very good player.
I would think about that long and hard,
but I also think that they really need
to address wide receiver as well. Sure.
>> Um so no, I I could see that happening,
but I also do know this if they don't.
>> They really really like Spencer Anderson
and they really like Dylan Cook. I I it
would not surprise me.
>> I think Hoffman's not a throwaway at all
either.
>> I don't think he's a throwaway at all. I
I think I think you'll see a legitimate
competition between Hoffman and Anderson
for left guard if they don't draft like
a guard higher up in the draft.
>> I think you see a legitimate competition
in training camp between those two guys,
but they really do like Spencer Anderson
a lot. And congratulations to Spencer,
brother. He just got married, so
>> Oh, did he?
>> Yeah,
>> that's awesome.
>> Uh Chris Alec, DK Pittsburgh Sports.
Great stuff as always. One of our
regulars here on the drive, albeit this
time about 3,000 miles away from home,
>> dude.
>> What? 20 2500 miles away. 3,000 sounds
better. We'll stick with that. Chris,
thanks for taking the time, man. Enjoy
yourself this week.
>> Yeah, we'll do, man. Thanks for having
me, guys. So, you know, I'm sure most of
most of our listeners have heard us talk
about this a couple times, but if you
haven't, uh Matt has done this a few
times. This is
>> my fourth or fifth.
>> I was going to say not as
>> my second time in Arizona.
>> Not as extensive as, you know, all the
times you've been to the combine and
things like that, but you have you have
done this uh annual league meetings a
few times. This was my first time.
Yesterday we were here, Matt, for our
first show and it was like us and the
New York Jets were the only people here
and it was quiet. They didn't even have
>> There's an empty Texans booth door left.
Yeah. Right.
>> The the media room, I think, had maybe
three or four people in it. Now it's got
30 or 40. Um, we had to struggle just to
get waters and coffee yesterday. Now,
now there's food and and beverages
everywhere around this place. So, it's
really picking up today.
>> I shouldn't complain, but yesterday I
kind of forgot. I made a rookie move and
I'm like I ate like a small breakfast
bar before we came over, but we started
later and I come over. I'm like, I
figured there'll be a ton of food and
coffee. I'll be fine. Nothing.
>> Nothing. Nothing.
>> Matt had to like steal a cup of coffee
and got yelled at.
>> I frankly stole it. Yeah. I I snuck in
somewhere I wasn't supposed to. Didn't
realize I was in doing something
illegal, but I did get a cup of coffee,
went home, and just feasted. I was
starving. Today is quite the opposite.
And frankly, these I mean people
watching on on YouTube might have some
idea, but I mean just the hustle and
bustle and the people that you're going
to hear walking by and you know this
hallway was pretty quiet yesterday and
everyone's setting up all the stuff
behind us and we walk in here and
there's an awesome breakfast and NFL
Network and ESPN and all these places
are set up broadcasting right next to us
and
>> Sher and Florio and K Adams and all
these people right behind us
>> and right in front of us is uh salon
number four there. They had all the NFC
coaches when we came out out from
breakfast. They were all rushing out and
they're everywhere. It's it's great.
It's it's a it's a pretty cool
environment.
>> And a certain host on this show uh might
have bumped into John Harbaugh
>> in his in his Giants gear and he goes,
"Ah, Steelers, you know, you guys are a
little bit better with me now. It's all
right.
>> Back to his good grace.
>> Have fun in there." But yeah, so it's uh
it was it's funny cuz you mention
>> these coaches are having a good time.
It's pretty relaxed. You mentioned last
year how you and Dale talked to Harbaugh
for a few minutes. He's just he just
must be a friendly guy because he saw my
he saw my Steelers polo. We almost
bumped into each other walking in. He
was like, "Hey, Steelers, man. Hey, come
on. We could be we could be friends now.
I'm in New York." Uh so yeah, it is it
is certainly certainly picked up here
today and expect that to continue to the
for the next few days. Um NFC head
coaches spoke today uh at their annual
breakfast. Uh AFC coaches will speak
tomorrow. Uh some GMs have spoken here
today and that will continue tomorrow as
well. So Matt, as we like to do a few
times a week and particularly I think
when we're at we're at events like this,
how about we start with a little news of
the day, all the moving and shaking here
on the grounds.
>> Yeah. Super quick before you do, I just
wanted to paint the picture like I
mentioned salon number four. Really all
it is is a ballroom and there are 16 big
round tables in there. What do they
hold? A dozen seats, something like
that.
>> It almost looks kind of like a wedding
reception. Yeah, exactly.
>> And everyone has their table and here's
where you sit
>> and there's a a sign that'll say,
>> you know, Harbaugh Giants, you know, and
there's, you know, Stfansky, Falcons,
>> the table right in front of us that I
can see there.
>> And anyone, including us, I mean, we
could have just walked up there and
either sat or hovered around Atlanta,
Chicago, Minnesota, whoever, and anyone
that has credentials can ask them
questions or, you know, that's the NFC
coaches breakfast. tomorrow is the AFC,
you know, and obviously there's more
ties to us, but um that's what's going
on. I mean, that's the mornings.
>> Yes, it was. There was actually, you
know, speaking of which, uh Kevin
O'Connell, the head coach of the
Minnesota Vikings, uh had his had his
availability this morning. Okay. Uh
there were a couple
>> I haven't heard any news from, you know,
things that they were that was said. So,
I'm psyched to get into this
>> and I I want to um potentially dig into
this one maybe kind of separately as its
as its own entity, but it's for for our
purposes. is it should probably lead off
this conversation. Kevin Oonnell had
great things to say about Brian
Angelico. Of course, Steelers, you know,
Mike McCarthy's first offensive
coordinator here uh and heading into his
first year as the head coach of the
Pittsburgh Steelers. Brian Angelico was
with the Vikings organization, of
course, working under Kevin O'Connell
>> and Kevin Oonnell had a lot of great
things to say about Angelico. He thinks
the world of him. He was sad to lose
him. He thinks it's a great hire for the
Steelers, right? Um, and so that was
>> the Pittsburgh reporter asked
>> Yes. I I believe it was both uh both
Mark Kabali and and Noah Strabean were
were there and just asked him a couple
questions about Angelico and he had he
had nothing but but great things to say
and and thinks it's um a well-earned
opportunity for him to to step up into a
role here with the Steelers.
>> So, we talked about that. It's one of
the harder conversations I have every
year and I've never had to do it with
the Steelers where they're building a
coaching staff, you know, like we my
other outlets I do this for every team
and it's always really hard to comment
on because frankly before he was a
candidate for the Steelers, I never
heard of Ryan Angelico. He was, you
know, and then it comes across, you
know, I Wikipedia scouted him, as I'd
like to say,
>> tight ends coach and I think he was
passing game coordinator. But I mean
like when immediately when you see tight
ends coach
tight end coach and running back coach
are kind of the lowest guy on the totem
pole that isn't a
>> um graduate assistant type or you know
quality control guy. It's a it's a great
job, don't get me wrong, but I mean
you're an NFL coach, but it's not
quarterback coach. It's not offensive
coordinator, you know. So immediately
you look at him like that doesn't blow
my doors off, but then you realize
passing game coordinator. Then you start
really digging in and you find quotes
from coaches he's worked with and
realize that guys like that are so
instrumental behind the scenes
>> that even people in our business would
have no idea how valuable they truly
are. Correct. You know
>> and that's what you you know like to get
into these circles and try and find out.
Here was the exact coach uh the exact
quote, pardon me, from Minnesota head
coach Kevin Oonnell on new Steelers
offensive coordinator Brian Angelico and
I quote, "What always kept coming out
was similar philosophical beliefs and
how you attack people specifically in
the pass game, but he has a really good
understanding of the run game and how to
marry the two together. He's been vital
for me in the red zone and our four
years together here. So when you look at
it, whether it's situational football,
early down success, how you tie it all
together, he is prepared for this
opportunity. It is long overdue for him
to get to coordinate.
>> Awesome. Exactly what you want to hear,
right?
>> Again, I mean, like
another thing people don't 100%
understand, nor do I exactly right now,
but I mean during the course of the
week, they will break down. You think
you have all this time you seven games
or seven days before between games.
>> I've told you Moes used to make that
joke all the time. Oh, we've got so
everyone in the NFL thinks we've got so
much time. You don't. You never have
time. You're always on to the next
thing.
>> Yes. And you're on the team flights. I'm
sure you see coaches from yesterday, you
know, Tomlin staff digging into the
opponent on the flight.
>> Well, we we get on the flight and the
video guys are handing out iPads. Yeah.
I mean, and they're going right right to
work on the flight.
>> Okay. You got the Vikings next week. Get
ready, you know. Yeah. There's not time.
But anyway, so thus I mean a big thing
that happens throughout the week is you
have this job. Hey tight ends coach, you
have this job. Hey, you know, uh,
assistant passing coordinator, you're in
charge of red zone. or whatever it is,
but
>> you're in charge of third and long,
you're in charge of red zone, you're in
break this into situational football,
right? Right. And whenever we practice
red zone, you basically run the offense,
you know, doesn't mean you call plays on
game day, but you built how to attack
the Steeler red zone or whatever it is.
>> You put the hay in the barn.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And everyone is on
the same page and there's a lot of
coordination that goes into that. And it
sounds like red zone was one of
Angelico's big things. it that that's
that's what I took from from Kevin
O'Connell today. Um, and you know, I'm
I'm very interested. You know, we talked
a little bit yesterday about the tight
end position, Matt. Yeah. And maybe this
was something we should have brought
into the into the conversation when we
were having it yesterday. That's that's
that's shame on me. But when you look at
um you know some of the tight ends that
Angelico worked with in Minnesota, you
know the T.J. Hawinson's types, the Josh
Oliver types,
>> and they went out of their way to go get
Hawinson. You know, they they paid and
got stole him or didn't steal, but they
made a trade within the division. I
mean, that doesn't happen very often. It
feels like feels like it's an exciting
time to be Pat Frier Mouthuth and
Darnell Washington. And potentially, as
we as we mentioned, it feels like not
with a a priority pick or anything, but
with those 12 draft picks, I'd be
surprised if they didn't come away with
another tight end to throw into
>> I think they absolutely will. Probably
the mid rounds and probably at a value.
Um, but it's funny you mentioned I
hadn't thought about that either. You
know, I immediately think McCarthy's
offense, you know, but sure you're
hiring a tight end coach
>> and it's funny because you mentioned
Josh Oliver. He's very Washington-like.
I mean, he's one of these real inline
mash your face blocker types that when
you face a ton of nickel or
>> 65 270.
>> Yeah. I mean, he's going to have a long
career doing that. Washington's a little
more special, you know? I mean, like
stands out. I mean, there's no tight end
in the league like Washington. He looks
like a tackle,
>> especially when he's rumbling down the
field and all those things. But they
have basically a Frier Mouth type in
Hawinson and a Washington type in Oliver
who's again 270. He's a one of the best
blocking tight ends in the league and
he'll play in this league as long as he
possibly can like a Mercedes Lewis.
>> Yes, that's that's a good comparison.
And I think those
>> types that he worked with in Minnesota,
that kind of pairs well with what he'll
have in in Pittsburgh.
>> That's kind of where it's going with it,
right? And I think that could be, you
know, I think we thought last year tight
end was going to be a real strength of
the offense and it
>> sort of underwhelmed.
>> It sort of underwhelmed I think just in
the grand scheme of expectations with
those two and John Smith coming off of a
massive year in Miami.
>> But you didn't want them on your fantasy
team, but overall the room did pretty
well. Yes. You know,
>> but maybe this is the year that it
really becomes a a true strength and a
true and a true matchup.
>> I'm hoping because I think it's one of
the best position groups on the team and
they are going to add something to it. I
I absolutely believe that.
>> Yes. So Matt, that was kind of the
biggest thing that that caught my eye uh
from the from the coaches speaking this
morning. I do want to get into more of
that obviously, but there were also some
of the GMs talking today.
>> Um
>> Oh, I thought it was just coaches.
>> So Omar Khan will speak tomorrow, but
GMs, some of the GMs are going today,
some are going tomorrow. It's not the
same exact clear-cut line in the sand
like it is for NFC and AFC with the head
coaches. I think it's just kind of up to
the GM's schedule. Yeah, if if that
makes sense. Kind of like it is at the
combine. You know, you have your
obligations that you have to fulfill,
but you could do them within your own
timeline or or Exactly.
>> Yeah. I'll knock it out today, too. Or
I'll talk it out today at 10 or
>> Exactly. Right. And so with that,
>> is that up at the podium by themselves?
That's in a different room,
>> I believe. So, that's in what we were
at.
>> Salon three down there. Yes. Where Matt
and I got our pictures doing our best
commissioner impressions yesterday.
>> Um, and yeah, it uh it was uh it was
pretty cool to see it all come to life
today. But with that, um, Andrew Barry
saying that, uh, the tweaks to Miles
Garrett's contract that we saw recently
are unrelated to a trade and that they
want him to be a Brown for life.
>> Yeah, this might be a bigger
conversation than we have time for this
segment because I don't believe it. I I
really don't. And I I guess this is sort
of new news, but late last week, we
didn't get a chance to really dig into
this conversation, but my take on it is
little over one year ago, Miles Garrett
demands a trade. I mean, flat out like
wrote this big thing.
I mean, it was no secret whatsoever.
>> And
we we know he went back and had a
ridiculously good year, by the way,
which is also influencing here. But he
he sold the the fans the narrative. I
believe in the Browns process. Now, they
also gave him a massive massive contract
and made him by far the highest paid
defensive player in NFL history a year
ago, which he deserves. And he went on
to prove he deserved it. But I believe,
and there's a little tinfoil hat here,
that Garrett had a heart-to-heart with
the Browns after he demanded a trade and
said, again, I'm guessing, okay, I'll
give you a year to prove to me that you
guys do have a plan and this is going
the right direction. I want to be part
of a winner. I understand my legacy. I
don't want to be the best pass rusher on
this on the seen this before, you I
mean, it's and my hunch is when the the
contract came out on my locked on show,
we started talking about it saying this
makes him more tradable.
The Browns, who frankly when Garrett
demanded the trade, I flat out said on
many airwaves, this is a gift,
>> was probably a blessing for them.
>> They should say thank you because
they're in such a bad spot. They can
maximize his talent. And I said at the
time, his his value is probably only
going to go down. I was wrong because he
had a better year and is even better now
than he's ever been,
>> man.
>> But if you're the Browns and you just
looked at the Max Crosby trade that
almost went through and think, what can
I get for the better version of that?
>> And Garrett's thinking the same thing.
Like, I just set the sack record in
games we were never winning. I may have
had five or six. I know people hate
hearing this, but this was true for TJ
in a lot of his career. How many big
leads did those guys play with?
>> Not many.
>> Not many. Yeah. I always say it all the
time. How many times in TJ's career have
they been up by 12 in Acushure
Hinesfield and everyone's waving the
towels and the whole world knows you
know they're throwing the ball.
>> Not many. And in Garrett's never
>> he's probably looking at like if I go to
the Lions or the Bills or whatever and
the Browns have to look at it like I
might get the value of like three first
round picks out of this guy. I mean at
least two.
>> The value is undeniable.
>> The value is undeniable. So, I don't
think this story's close to being over,
>> especially when you kind of combine it
with the Max Crosby backdrop that you
just mentioned. Yeah, I think Crosby's a
year or two younger, but Miles Garrett
is the And that's not a knock that's not
a knock on Crosby. He's great.
>> Miles Garrett is the defensive player of
the year. He just broke the NFL single
season sack record. Uh, and so, yeah,
that that is an interesting
conversation. And you're right, I don't
think this story is over as much as
Cleveland can and I'm sure will try and
throw Cole.
>> Exactly what they should say. It's
exactly what they should say,
>> but he can't be possibly thrilled with
the Are you happier now being a Brown
than you were one year ago when you
demanded the trade? How could the answer
possibly be yes?
>> I I can't imagine so. It feels like
you've taken even not drastically, but
more of a step back here than
>> I'm looking through his lens. I'm like,
we're still at least as far at least
they're turning things into picks and I
see that there's a vision here and they
had a good draft class. So, okay, that's
step one. Now we're a year away from
being a year away,
>> right? They've got no offensive line.
>> They have no Yeah. I mean, who's the
quarterback? I mean,
>> they've got five quarterbacks, Matt. You
know what they say about quarterbacks.
When you have five, you have none.
>> They're distant fourth in their
division, even with a really good
defense and the best defensive player
out there. So, he's got to be thinking,
man, I'm I'm less happy being a Brown
now than I was one year ago when I
demanded a trade. I mean, that's that's
to me is the logic. Now, that being
said, one more layer to this. Think as
those around you think if I'm the
Browns, I want to hold this off.
>> Yeah.
>> Past the draft because what I want to do
is I if I if I really intend on trading
him, I want to do it after the draft
>> to get 2027 next year fixed. Right.
>> Yes.
>> Or even wait till the trade deadline
when the Lions are seven and one, the
Browns are one and seven and he's got 12
sacks and is unblockable. I'm like,
"Okay, you want this, you know, Detroit
or whoever, Buffalo, whatever." Now, we
can talk about all kinds of future pick,
you know,
>> that that makes a ton of sense.
>> I don't think the story's close to being
written. I
>> I don't either. And there's one kind of
more thing here about the contract
language of the tweaks that they made to
his deal that I want to discuss with
you, okay? And we've got to
>> I didn't 100% understand it. And my only
interpretation was why change the the
the the
We can get back to it on the on the
other side, but I mean,
>> yeah. Why change the language of the
contract if it's not a precursor for
something else?
>> It made me think they had a handshake
deal when they signed it originally.
Like I want a year from now if we his
agent says a year from now I want you to
change this this uh wording if we
choose.
>> Again I'm guessing but that that's the
only thing that adds up.
>> Matt, a ongoing story from this week and
one that I think is going to probably
linger
to training camp if I if I had to guess.
These next couple days might really pick
this up too. Get the snowball rolling
down the hill. You know,
>> uh, according to all the conversation
yesterday and today, the NFL and the NFL
RA, which is the NFL referees
association,
>> you don't hear that very often, but I
bet you're going to hear it more and
more.
>> Let me let me just real quick set the
set set the scene for everybody. I think
if you're listening to this show in
March, if you're listening to a 247
football network in March, you probably
know a thing or two about football.
You've probably heard of the NFL PA, the
NFL Players Association. You've we've
had instances in the past, we've had
conversations in the past where the
NFLPA and the NFL have collective
bargaining agreements. How many games
are going to be played in a season? Uh
what are certain parameters on salaries
and salary caps and things like that and
franchise tags and and travel and and
all these all sorts of things pract how
much they're allowed to practice and
what training camp can look like and
you're familiar all that stuff is
collectively bargained between the
league and the NFL PA, the NFL players
association. Well, what I don't think
everybody is hip to is that there is
also an NFL RA, the NFL referees
association, and they have the same type
of contracts with the league that the
players association does. Parame they're
not as powerful, but
>> I bet they are not as powerful, but they
certainly have a big big role and a big
big effect on this. And if you'll all
remember back in 2012, there was a
situation where there was a strike with
the referees association to start the
year. That was the famous game actually
involving Aaron Rogers, funny enough, in
the Green Bay Packers in Seattle to open
that season. And Aaron Rogers throws the
or I can't remember if it was Aaron
Rogers or Russell Wilson, but throws the
Hail Mary on the last play of the game.
And there's two replacement refs and one
standing in the end zone signaling
touchdown and the other one's there
incomplete pass. And it was famously
called the fail Mary and there was a
bunch of controversy around that moment.
Well, Matt, uh, according to everybody
here, boots on the ground. It sounds
like the NFL and the NFL RA are far away
from, uh, from negotiations and, uh, and
agreements on a new contract, and the
NFL has begun the process to start
hiring replacement refs.
>> Wow. Okay. I mean, that that's putting
the pressure on them. They must feel
like they're pretty far off. Now, I know
about football. You know about football.
We don't know a ton about labor
negotiations and whatnot, too. It's
another topic that I am not going to
claim to be an expert on. Maybe this is
step one of just putting pressure on
your opponent. That's a tactic.
>> Much much like the Miles Garrett, we're
not trading them conversations.
Everything is about controlling the
narrative and and and winning the
winning the negotiation.
>> Absolutely. And which is going to be
part of this putting pressure on your
opponent to get the best deal you
possibly can. There's tactics involved,
of course,
>> but not what you want to hear, you know.
I mean, as we sit here, what at the end
of March?
>> End of March. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, you would hope that these
these aren't the stories you want to be
talking about for between now and
opening day.
>> Yes. Yes. I think that's a good way to
put it.
>> Most of our listeners like, "Boy, I just
hope this goes away and we have to hear
about it again."
>> Exactly. Right. Right. Um, and there's a
very good chance that could be the case.
Yeah. There's also a chance, like I
said, that this could linger into the
summer and up to the start of the
regular season because we all know
that's the classic, I think, kind of
11th hour of of negotiations, right?
Sure. We've seen this.
>> Deadlines get things done, you know?
Right. deadlines get things done. We've
seen this before with NFL PA
negotiations where it's like, "Oh my
goodness, could there be a lockout?
Could there be a strike? Could there be
a delay to the start of the season?" And
then they get something done in the 11th
hour. And so there's a very obviously
real possibility that that's the case.
Uh but the NFL has compiled a list of uh
college officials to recruit. Wow.
>> Um and they're uh you know expected to
add some replay enhancements. We
discussed that yesterday that would
accompany uh this to make life a little
bit easier on those replacement refs.
And
>> I got a question for you about this now,
now I think about it.
>> So, does the SEC have refs?
>> Yes, every conference has their own
refs.
>> Okay. And they're ACC from the ACC or
from Big 12 or whatever. Okay.
>> You know, all the way down into, you
know,
course I thought so, but
>> Okay.
>> And they work other games. So, for
example, sorry to cut you off there, but
like
>> the national championship game was
Indiana and Miami. Big Big 10, ACC. I
believe it was a Big 12 officiating crew
that did the national championship game.
>> Someone's got good ratings.
>> They also they also do that in the bowl
games and like, you know, in the
beginning of the season, Ohio State will
play Texas, you know, like in a
non-conference game and they'll bring in
an ACC officiating crew.
>> But just like the Super Bowl for the
national championship game, it's the
best crew.
>> Yes. Good ratings. If you're getting
those big games, if you're getting in
the, you know, the playoffs and the
college football championship, you
obviously have a pretty good reputation.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. That's exactly what the the
preface I wanted to lend to this. Okay.
So, you said and Miami plays Indiana in
the national title game and they bring
in a Big 12 staff, which they probably
think, I'm just going to assume is the
best referee staff in college football
that's not part of these two
conferences.
>> Correct.
>> Okay.
>> I would imagine that that's the
that's who they want. That's the hiring
front.
neutral. So they can't say, "Oh, he's
just favoring the Big 10 team, you know,
but and has very high ratings." Yes.
>> And they say, "It's an honor. We're
offering you this job for this day
first. You can refuse it if you want or
whatever." Okay. Well, here's where I'm
going with this. I assume the NFL
reaches out to that exact same crew,
says, "You're the best. Do you want to
be our replacement crew?" Wow, that
sounds awesome. But the rules are really
different. Really different.
>> Cool. And I mean that to me that's
almost like learning a new language. I'm
trying to think as those around you
think. If I'm that ref going I'm really
good at refing college. It'd be like if
someone asked me
>> it's almost like it's almost like going
from algebra to calculus.
>> The example I was to use is like if
someone asked me to talk about Pitt and
WVU like it's football but it's I don't
know the saying.
>> Or if someone asked you and I to be on
TV like to do a television studio
football show.
>> Right. Right. Right. Right. or you know
I I have to do it in three minute
increments as opposed to three-hour
increments or
>> I think maybe like a lot like if you're
a radio if you're if you're uh if you're
Rob King and you're doing the Steelers
broadcast on radio to all of a sudden
you got to go do a national broadcast
for ABC or the rules are just different
>> and the way you call games on radio is
way different than you call games on TV.
It's it's in the same ecosystem but
there's a lot of differences. I mean, it
wouldn't be like asking me to talk about
tennis, but I mean, but still, there's a
lot of nuances and rule books take a
long time to learn and
>> the catch rules are different. The down
down by contact rules,
>> the speed of the game is way different
than the stadiums and where the play
clocks,
>> overtime rules, all these things.
>> So, what I'm saying is, okay, NFL goes
to that Big 12 uh group. Hey, you're our
first choice. You're awesome. Okay,
thank you, NFL. That sounds great. But
what's the chances I'm actually gonna
get the gig?
>> Am I gonna relearn everything for
>> two weeks?
>> For two weeks until you guys seal the
deal. And you know what I mean? Like I'm
happy where I'm at. Leave me alone. You
know, like
like it it would be hard for me to say
yes to that job.
>> That's a great point.
>> Knowing I'm probably just going to get
replaced as soon as the deal gets signed
>> and then does and Big 12 still want me
right. All of a sudden did I lose?
>> They're going to play games with or
without me. Did I did I lose my seat at
the table at the top of the the
collegiate pecking order just to go work
two or three weeks in the NFL?
>> Right. Which is reason number 100 that
the NFL should have a minor league
system. You bring up the the best guys
from the
>> Morgantown Steelers. You know what I
mean? The State College Eagles or
whatever. You know,
>> State College Eagles. Yeah.
>> But I mean, if I'm the if I'm a great
college ref, I have a good gig. I'm not
saying yes to that. Uh, you know what I
and all the different angles of this
that I had thought about, that's the
one. That's a great point by you because
Yeah. Why am I going to lose my seat at
the table?
>> Yeah.
>> To go to go work a couple weeks in the
NFL and then it might
>> I know this language, but I got to learn
one that's similar but not the same.
>> And if I go up there
>> and I'm never going to go that country
>> and I make a bad call or I get something
wrong. I'm going to get crushed
nationally and I'm never going to get my
thinks I'm an idiot. Everybody thinks
I'm dingus. You're not gonna get any
benefit of the doubt in that position. I
mean, not even close.
>> Yeah, don't sign me up for that.
>> That's You know what? I hadn't
considered that, but that's a very good
thought process uh for you to bring to
the table. So, apparently
>> it's pretty good being an SEC ref. I'm
sure
>> I been doing this for 20 years and you
know,
>> I imagine that that's I imagine that's a
fun gig. I imagine that's a pretty good
gig with uh with gainful employment.
Certainly. Yeah. Uh, one difference
though, Matt, that I think is important
in some of this language here in the
reports is that uh, according to a
league source, they want to start
training new replacement officials
beginning May 1st. Okay, so a little
over about a month from now.
>> Okay,
>> when this happened in 2012,
>> again, you have to get trained
>> big time. It's
>> not just like here's a book, learn it,
you know,
>> big time. When this happened in 2012,
they didn't start the they didn't start
the uh the referee training until July.
So that was one of the things of like
we're going to learn from our mistake
last time. We didn't give these guys
enough time to prepare. Like you just
mentioned all the new rules, the new
changes, the differences and just how
the way the games are governed. One
catch is in in college football. One
foot is a catch in college football, two
feet in the NFL.
>> And those are the easy ones. I mean I
mean the rules are way deeper than that.
>> Exactly right. Like the difference in
you know in college if your knee's down
you're down. It doesn't matter if you're
touched or not. Whereas opposed to
>> Mr. Jeremy Fowler walking by.
>> Jeremy Fowler, formerly of this parish
in Western Pennsylvania, walking by
here. Um, so at least they're saying or,
you know, addressing that and we're
going to give these guys two extra
months to prepare and start training,
which I think is definitely important,
>> train them as much as possible. I just I
mean,
>> but what if you're training your fourth
or fifth choice crew and not the best in
the not the A team? Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
I don't I mean I just see a lot of room
for error here.
>> Well, there certainly is. There there
certainly is. Um, so that is what I
think like you you said it well, Matt.
It's not what we want to be talking
about this time of year. I don't think
it's what much NFL fans want to be
hearing or discussing. They don't get
just but put the referees out on the
field, let them do their job, get it
done properly, you know, give us his and
that's the that's the other part of
this. If it does end up coming to a
replacement ref situation that people
are going to hate, there's going to be
more parameters for review. They're
going to they're going to expand that's
already
>> they're going to expand that tomorrow.
>> They're talking about that tomorrow. So
they're going to expand the video
elements and so that would be something
that people at home would notice and
would be bothered by one more thing to
focus on.
>> One more thing to focus by. One more
additional piece of I guess potential
controversy if you want to label it that
way. And also Matt just
>> I I think there's not many things that
all sports fans agree on, right? There's
not there's not many things in society
that we that we all agree on. But I do
think one of them pretty unanimously
unanimously across the board. If you ask
football fans, if you ask fans of any
other sport too, yes, they want review,
but they want it to be a speedy, quick,
expedited process. They don't want to
see the referees going to the monitor
multiple times a game. They don't want
to see it taking two or three minutes to
make the decision.
>> I have a feeling that a lot of
>> they want the microwave version. Of
course,
>> they want the microwave version of video
review. Uh, and I have a feeling that a
lot of this would be the opposite of
that. It would be more frequent. It
would be longer reviews. It would be
clunkier. It would slow the game down.
And again, like that's something I don't
care if you're a Steelers fan, a Ravens
fan, a Cowboys fan, an Eagles fan,
that's something that nobody wants to
see.
>> True. Now, as you were saying that, I'm
like, that's kind of demanding. Like, I
want every play call to be right. And I
want to be super quick. Oh, there's
nothing else you want.
>> I also want my cake and I want to eat
it, too.
>> Yeah. And I want to eat it too. And then
I want another cake. And then I want
another cake. And I never want it to be
a bad cake.
>> Some ice cream.
>> Right. Exactly. Like, of course,
everybody wants it quick and perfect.
>> It's asking a lot.
>> It sure is. like never never miss a ball
or strike call. Like bring in the robot.
>> I'm going to miss one or two, you know,
right?
>> But then you bring in the robot umps and
everyone's like, "Well, what happened to
the human element of the game?
>> You can't always get what you want." But
if you try sometimes,
>> you just might find
>> you get what you need. Joining us now, a
special guest. You know, his work covers
the Steelers for the Athletic, Mike
DeFabo. Mike, what's up, dude? Are you
uh you enjoying the Arizona sunshine?
You know, nice to uh to get out of the
northeast winter here for a few days.
Yeah, I mean I'm I'm missing those low
20s temperatures and the bipolar weather
we've been having in Pittsburgh, but no,
it's unbelievably beautiful here right
now. Perfect weather. Uh great to be
indoors in the air conditioning with you
guys, though.
>> Absolutely. We're looking forward to it.
Pretty cool party tonight uh here that
I'm going to get to experience for the
first time.
>> Uh I was I was laughing with Matt
though. I brought, you know, brought my
jacket, my pants, my shirt, everything.
Forgot dress socks for the party. So, I
am I am going to have to get some dress
socks.
>> I can take care of you there. I'm a good
friend like that. Oh, you got an extra
set.
>> All right.
>> I could hook you up. Okay.
>> Matt Matt forgot his slacks and had to
go get a pair. I forgot dress socks. You
know, we're just uh we're just a
welloiled machine over here.
>> I told you though, this is like the NFL
wedding. Um the first time I went to it,
I texted my wife and said, "This is the
best wedding I ever have been to." There
was like a 25piece band. The guys were
wearing tuxedos.
>> Yeah.
>> There was an oldfashioned bar. I ate
around the world. I had sushi. I had
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Uh, Italian plate, steak.
>> Now you're speaking
>> carving station.
>> It's usually not the path I go because
I'm consuming liquor and whatnot, but
the ice cream bar is unbelievable. I
mean, like the desserts are insane.
>> They have a petting zoo for kids.
>> Last year they had hermit crab races.
>> The hermit crab races. Yeah.
>> Hermit crab races.
>> With like Steeler symbols on them and
cowboy symbols on them and you bet on
the cowboy hermit crab or whatever.
>> That's pretty. All right. Well, I was
excited for tonight. Now you just put it
over the top with Hermit the Hermit crab
racing here. I mean, come on.
>> No gambling on it. I don't know about
gambling in uh
>> in this state if that's legal,
especially when it comes to hermit crab.
>> That's a good point. Your secret's safe
with me. Don't worry, I won't tell
anybody. Uh Mike, let's jump into it
with you. Obviously, some stuff uh as it
pertains to here that we want to discuss
with you. Some Steelers related stuff.
Uh I want to piggyback off of what Matt
and I were just talking about in our our
first hour of the show here as we kick
off hour number two. What's your
temperature check? What's your vibe
around this kind of uh current stalemate
standoff between the league and the
referees association? Uh do you think
that this is just it? It's the right
time in the calendar. They're posturing
for kind of the narrative and
negotiations or do you think this could
be something that could linger, you
know, deep into the summer and close to
the regular season?
>> I mean, we've seen once before that it
did linger into the season and Aaron
Rogers was a part of it and not a big
fan of those replacement referees.
Right.
>> And referees are funny because they have
a tough job and they're not always very
good at it and it's easy to criticize
them, but when you don't have them and
you have people that are not as prepared
to do the job, then you even see how
difficult that job really is. So, you
hope for quality control and for the
betterment of the game that they do get
this resolved, but again, they weren't
able to last time.
>> So, speaking of Rogers, two-part
question, lowhanging quick answer. Do
you think he's going to be a Steeler in
the starter in week one. Part two,
assuming that gets done before the
draft, or if you don't think so, let's
go down that road, too. Do you think
they draft one or not? I'm really on the
fence if it's the right move. So, you
know, it's interesting because around
the combine time, I talked with people,
I think, at all levels of the
organization from players who had been
in communication with Rogers, you know,
through the public comments and and
stuff that Omar Khan and Mike McCarthy
made and other decision makers. And
their whole feeling was Aaron Rogers was
going to decide sometime in March. And
they thought that it was likely and
there was optimism that he would sign
with the Steelers. I really got the
sense that they believe that they would
have an answer coming into this meeting
and they don't.
>> We got one more day. I was just double
checking the calendar here. It's the
30th. Okay.
>> So, I think I think even the people who
are most intimately involved in in these
discussions are a bit surprised that
it's taken as long as it has, but I
think that it really is trending in that
direction. I think that the overwhelming
likelihood is Aaron Rodgers is leading
the Steelers onto the field week one.
Now, when it comes to drafting a
quarterback,
>> I mean, the the the difficult thing is
this was supposed to be a talent-rich QB
class,
>> right?
>> It's basically falling apart because
you've got guys that either failed to
meet expectations like Nusmeer or like
Drew Aller. You've got guys who
>> chose to stay in school
>> and then you've got both like the Lenor
Celler guys.
>> So, really your only option early would
be Tai Simpson. I would be almost
shocked if they go that route. Me too.
>> I think that the 15 college starts is
going to be such a turnoff for this
team. Yep.
>> And that's gonna be such a deterrent for
them.
>> So then you're talking about who else
would they go for? You know, they had a
handful of quarterbacks that they met
with at the combine. They also hosted
Carson Beck.
>> They're going to be familiar with
Nusmeer.
>> They are very familiar with Nusmeer.
They met with him at the Senior Bowl. Um
so they've already had a sit down
meeting with him. Um, I think Carson
Beck is interesting. I know the fan base
isn't all in on him. They seem to be
very against that idea, but they brought
him in for a reason. And I think that,
uh, he's really the opposite in terms of
versus Ty Simpson. He is a guy with
nearly three times as much starting
experience. not all that good, but I
think that when you're talking about
drafting a quarterback in like the
fourth round. So, to answer your
question, Matt,
>> I could see I could see them using like
a fourth round type pick on a
quarterback, but not something early and
not something aggressive.
>> I I don't think either one of the top
two rounds will be a quarterback. No,
>> I mean, if Nuser's there in the third, I
understand. If another one of these
names, Cole Payton, etc., I understand.
But I'm kind of just torn. Is it worth
it at all?
Yeah, it's a good point because um I
mean I think there have been times where
the Steelers have had a lot of QB2s on
their roster but no QB1.
>> You know, it's like the guy in your
fantasy football league that tries to
trade you a bunch of backups for your
starter. You know, having a a Mason
Rudolph, having a Kenny Picket, and
having a Mitch Trabiscy doesn't equal a
QB1. You can't add them up together. So,
>> they don't all equal Ben.
>> Right.
>> Can't build one in the aggregate. So, I
mean, it's not the wor even if you had
Rogers come in, it's not the worst idea
to take another quarterback in the mid
round and then that guy also get the
Will Howard experience because Rogers
was an extremely willing mentor to Will
Howard. He should be
>> That's one of the biggest allures. I
just want someone to hang with Rogers
for a year.
>> And that happened from quite literally
Aaron Rogers very first day on the
practice field. I watched him there work
with Will Howard on his footwork. Aaron
Rogers was like specifically
>> first. Yeah, I remember when Rogers
wasn't even practicing.
>> He was wearing sneakers.
>> Yeah, he he didn't even work out, but he
was working with Will Howard and that
continued throughout the year. So, that
would be maybe the advantage to doing
so. But I get your point. If you use
that pick on a
>> what, an inside linebacker instead,
right?
>> You know, and just save that.
>> Still planning on taking one in the
first round next year. What's it get
you? and you're probably cutting Rudolph
or trading Rudolph
>> or or you trade that, you know, whatever
fourth round pick for a pick in 2027 and
that's part of uh the excess draft
capital you can use to then take your
aggressive swing. So, I mean, I could
see the the argument for just rolling
with the current quarterback room.
>> Um, so I think it probably hinges upon
how much they actually like these guys
in the draft and what does Rogers say
and when.
>> One thing I would throw in just because
I I want our listeners to remember this.
I remember vividly the that first OTAA
session. He had signed like five minutes
before,
>> right?
>> And I remember just every everyone on
the planet was staring at Rogers, of
course, and we were on the air and all I
could think was this guy is so engaged
for every second that his body is on the
football field. He's either coaching up
Frier or Howard or Washington or Metaf
or he's sitting there with the
quarterback coaching the offensive
coordinator getting coached up. I mean,
every second he was engaged
>> and he he even led a meeting every
Thursday. It was a playerled meeting
where he stood up in front of the room.
Will Howard was the guy on the computer
um you know working that thing and I
think for the most part he was very
wellreceived by his teammates. Now Aaron
Rogers is by his own definition a
perfectionist and he demanded excellence
and perfection out of his teammates.
Sometimes we saw that spill over to him
going and getting in Roman Wilson's
face, but really overwhelmingly I think
that those interactions were positive
because he was demanding specific
things. And you look at Mike McCarthy's
offense, you know, the whole West Coast
offense is based on timing and
precision.
>> And if a guy is not coming out of his
break when you need him to, when you're
at a certain point in your drop and in
your progression, it doesn't work. And
that's why
>> five and a half yards, right? Not 5
yards, not six yards, 5 and 1/2 yards.
>> That's why he's like that.
>> 6 inches in front of the numbers, not
eight, six inches in front of the
numbers.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And so that's where that all came from.
And and that's where I think that
>> that's some of the extra benefit of
Rogers. Like we know that maybe his
mobility isn't what it was. The deep
ball was more inconsistent than I
expected to be last year. Um, but he
still has the arm talent and more than
anything, he has the mental makeup to be
the leader of this offense. Mike DeFabo
of The Athletic with us here at the
League meetings on Steelers Nation
Radio, Steelers Audio Network. Okay, I
guess then this leads me to
let's say Aaron Rogers decides, you know
what, I'm retiring. I'm sailing off into
the sunset. Maybe I don't want to face
down the replacement refs again the
first couple weeks in September. Then
what becomes the plan for the
organization? I Is it Will Howard, Mason
Rudolph, another draft pick, you know,
go to Latroe and see what happens? Is it
bring in another um veteran type guy, a
Kirk Cousins, a Derek Carr, a Jimmy
Garopolo, some of the names that are
still available? If Aaron Rogers is not
a Pittsburgh Steeler, you know, by mini
camp, by, you know, training camp in
that summer kind of timeline, what do
you think the plan is? What's plan B for
the Steelers if it's not number eight?
>> Yeah, and that'll be a good question
that we'll get to ask Mike McCarthy
today. But, you know, my sense is that
the Steelers do have a lot of faith in
Will Howard. There are people, you know,
Mike McCarthy's on record praising him
and talking about how much he likes the
potential of Will Howard because of his
big frame because of the fact that he
won a national championship at Ohio
State. That's all appealing to this
team. Um, and other people within the
organization also are are quite high on
Will Howard and his potential. I think
that Will Howard would be given an
opportunity to compete for the starting
job and then I think they would fill out
if they brought in I think they would
likely draft a quarterback like you know
that day four day three or round four uh
round three type pick to round out the
room but if they brought in a veteran
you know from what I've heard it would
be to compete
>> with the the rest of the room not
necessarily the sign the guy give him
the QB1 title
>> so They currently have five picks on the
first two days, which is great. They
have an immense amount of draft capital
compared to the rest of the league.
Quarterback aside, Rogers aside, what
positions with those five picks would
you write down in blood is going to be
one of the five?
>> Offensive guard surprisingly has turned
into, I think, maybe the most glaring
hole on the roster right now. You look
at what they did in free agency. They
got a wide receiver, too. They uh you
know upgraded the defensive front, added
some depth there. They got a quarterback
to start opposite Joey Porter Jr. Uh
added some safety options. The one thing
that they really didn't do is find a
legitimate upgrade and replacement for
Isaac Samalo. Now, I know that they have
Brock Hoffman and Spencer Anderson. The
way that I
>> They're not terrible options, and I'm
not saying you're implying they are,
>> right? But but my read on this or the
way that I would look at it if I'm the
Steelers, you've already invested two
first round picks, a second round pick,
and a fourth from the offensive line
with the goal of this group not just
being pretty good, but being dominant.
>> Sure.
>> And the only way you can continue along
that same trajectory is with a guy that
is an upgrade to Isaac Amalu or a guy
who at least is at that same caliber.
And so I wouldn't count out even in the
first round going with an offensive
guard. Um, but certainly I think within
the first three rounds that will be a
position that they're looking to
address. Wide receiver once felt like
the obvious need. It's diminished to a
degree because of Michael Pitman. You
don't feel that urgency to get the first
round guy, but I still wouldn't be
surprised if they went wide receiver
first or second round. Um, that makes a
lot of sense to me. And honestly, going
back to the offensive line, this
Brderick Jones injury,
>> that's what I was going to ask you next
if you had any any clarity on on his
next situation.
>> I mean,
>> nobody seems to have any clarity.
>> The the way I understand it, like
someone has said to me, it's not a
death, it's not necessarily a death
sentence for his career. I mean,
>> but that's not the most encouraging
framing of it either. It's not like, oh,
he's going to be fine.
>> Like, it's so miles. So, I think that I
think that that could it could be
something that lingers like and the
other part about this is they likely
would have or should have probably
picked up Broadick's fifth year option
because you look at the fact that it
would come in around 20 million. Dan
Moore Jr. allowed the most sacks in the
league and turned around and got 20
million by four years. Okay, that's the
going rate for a starting offensive
tackle in this league. But
>> not even good ones.
>> Right. Right.
So, I feel like, you know, now it seems
unlikely that they would pick up
Broadick's fifth year option. You know,
sooner than later, you're going to need
a new starting left tackle, whether it's
week one of this season because
Broadick's not healthy in time or it's
next year. So, I I feel like all of the
sudden offensive tackle that looked like
they had shorted up for the the long
haul, that's now becoming more of a a
question mark for the team. And then I
guess another thing would be a nice pick
would be a true pure free safety with
some speed some speed on the back end.
>> You know, Jaquan Brisk the team the team
thinks that he has the versatility to
play uh you know a variety of positions
within the secondary including free
safety.
You know he was kind of inconsistent.
That was kind of the knock on him is his
eye discipline wasn't really great when
he was in center field there. So, if you
got a guy that um you know, at least
gives you another option there, not to
mention, I mean,
>> he's going to help on special teams and
Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, I think
>> on a one-year deal,
>> I think all those positions would make
sense. And I think, you know, in the
middle rounds, if you can get an upgrade
to Blake Harrison, uh that linebacker,
>> Sharky, he still on the team.
>> Is it maybe feel like a Cordderero
Patterson type situation
>> in terms of
>> getting cut? I I think they maybe have
to wait and see how the draft pans out.
Um, but I just feel like they've got two
guys in the mold of like Peyton Wilson
and Patrick Queen are kind of similar
where they're both that rangy coverage
inside linebacker.
>> You know, you trust him in sub packages,
>> but they're both better if you've got
that real downhill force, the Landon
Roberts type player.
>> Banger. Yeah.
>> And and I think that Malik Carrison, I
mean, he was injured for some of the
year, and I don't think that he was what
they were expecting uh when he was on
the field healthy. So, I feel like if
you And this is a really, really good
inside linebacker class.
>> It's good safety, too.
>> Good safeties, too.
>> And cornerback, actually.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, they've got all these picks and
I'm naming all these positions, but you
know,
>> they can do all of them.
>> That's the other wild thing. Like,
>> I wouldn't even count on a corner as
early as the first round if they like a
guy enough because I know
>> true outside corner.
>> I know. I know that they got Jamal Dean.
I know that they got him. But still, I
think that if they the right corner was
there, I think that they would see an
opportunity.
>> Very interesting. Uh any any
restructures or anything coming down the
line? Highmith, TJ Watt still still in a
fine cap position that you don't have to
consider that.
>> Yeah, you know, I I think that I guess
DK could be a candidate, too.
>> They could go that route if they need
to, but they don't need to right now.
And so I think that that's kind of a
last resort. If they were in a position
where they had an opportunity to bring
in a player, they needed to create the
cap space. But Omar, remember, I mean,
he made his reputation by being a master
with the salary cap and moving those
numbers around. And right now, he's put
the Steelers in an excellent cap
position right now.
>> Exceptional.
>> And and so right now, you don't have to,
but you know, things could change down
the line.
>> Last thing I got for you along those
lines, too. You you expect some
extensions maybe in camp too, you know,
Porter, etc.
>> Herbic.
>> Yeah, I think that you know, all all
those guys from Omar Khan's first draft
class,
>> Benton maybe.
>> Rapids fast, doesn't it?
>> Pretty much all of them, you could make
the case that they um deserve an
extension. So, a guy like Joey Porter
Jr., I think that probably will get
done.
>> Um the one that I wonder about is Nick
Herbig because obviously his performance
merits it and you would love to have
that guy long term. My question, and I
don't have an answer to this, I'm
speculating. What would he want
>> if
>> I'd want quite a bit?
>> Well, and the other question is, would
you want to
basically prove yourself this year and
hit the open market and really see what
your value is on the open bet on
yourself?
>> Does he want the money now? Does he want
the security? Um, do they make it
financially, uh, you know, situation
that makes sense for him? Or would he
want to say, "I'm betting on myself this
year. I'm gonna play this out and next
year I'm going to be a coveted guy that
more teams than just the Steelers are
going to be interested in throwing some
money at." It's a lot to ponder, a lot
to consider. Great stuff with our friend
Mike DeFabo. Make sure you're checking
out all his work in the Athletic. Uh
enjoy all the hustle and bustle today.
And we will uh we'll see you at the
we'll see you at the dinner party a
little bit later.
>> Can't wait. I'll be uh saving you a spot
over by the oldfashioned bar. Over by
the old fashioned hermit crab. I want to
make Yeah, I'll see you by the Hermit
crab. I was say I'm trying to get front
row. I'm trying to get I'm trying to get
floor seating for the uh for the hermit
crab race. I can't wait. Great stuff.
>> That might be a Florida only thing. I
don't know.
>> I don't know. Wouldn't they wouldn't
they have like gators or something else
race if it was Florida?
>> But last year was Florida and it was
hermit crabs. I don't know.
>> Oh boy. Well, we'll see what we'll see.
>> Scorpions or something out here.
>> Yeah, that's right. It's scorpion.
>> Some kind of rattlesnake. Some kind of
rattlesnake. Yeah. tarantulas or
something like that. We'll we'll see.
We'll report back tomorrow live at the
NFL annual league meetings. And joining
us now, a special guest, ESPN senior
reporter, very special, formerly of
Western Pennsylvania, formerly covering
the Pittsburgh Steelers for ESPN. Used
to stay in Latroe in the same dorm wing
as myself and Matt Williamson not too
long ago. That's right.
>> Jeremy Fowler, what's up, partner? How
you doing?
>> Just a I'm good, man. We were just a few
legends dorming it up together.
>> That's it. That's
>> living the frat life. Yeah, very much
so. We St. Vincent
>> I heard you were a formidable player on
the hoop court at St. Vincent, too. The
rumor has it back in the day.
>> Yeah, I could play a little bit. I play
a little bit. I still try to play, but
as you know, I'm getting I'm in my
mid-40s now, so it's tough tough to get
around. It
>> gets a little bit tougher. He's got the
height, though, for sure. Does Jeremy
Fowler. Well, thanks for taking the
time, man. Let's jump into it here. I'm
sure you know where we want to start.
Uh, what's the latest on Aaron Rogers?
What are you hearing? Are we any closer
to the finish line than the start of
this thing? You know, I yeah, I wish I
could tell you there was some sort of
one-year or two-year deal finalized
right now, but I just don't sense a lot
of momentum at the moment. That's not a
reason to worry. I just, you know, when
I check with people with the team, they
said, "Hey, you know, hopefully we find
some out before the draft." But, uh
there's really no firm timeline right
now. So, I I think it's in the same
place. I still expect him to be a
Steeler and uh you know, it seems like
the the relationship is good and it was
a good experience for him and Mike
McCarthy knows him well, but
they haven't had to pivot yet to
anything else. So, it's just with Aaron
Rogers and his timelines for multiple
offseasons, like it's always been an
unpredictable proposition. So, it's hard
to really know exactly what to expect.
Um, you know, I know they've done a
pretty good amount of homework on this
draft class. I don't know what that
means. It's because it turned out to be
not an overly strong one depthwise, but
you know, maybe in the middle rounds did
they look at somebody and then, you
know, you have the Will Howard
conversation. I mean, when you talk to
people with the team, they do speak up
Will Howard. You think that's real, huh?
Yeah,
>> they're at least enthusiastic about him
or
>> probably I mean, right. I think there
layers to it. It's a layer discussion.
Do I think that they're high enough on
him where he's, you know, he's got a
start right now? No. But, um, I I was
told they were really impressed by how
he handles the huddle, how he handles
the operation. Like, he was ahead of the
game with that stuff, with like the
nuances of the position. So, because of
that, they do like him. Um, now, do I
think they're ready to start him? No.
But, uh, yeah, it's somewhere in the
middle. I I Are they overselling him a
little bit in the absence of Aaron
Rogers? Maybe. Uh, but I do think
there's genuine interest in what he can
do and how he can develop.
>> So, you mentioned pivoting away from
Rogers. Did you didn't have any
inclination that they were in on Kyler
Murray or they would go to a Cousins or
a car or anything like that if Rogers
fell through? Or maybe that is a
possibility at this point. I
>> I just haven't heard anything hard and
fast with that. I I definitely don't
think they were on Kyler Murray or any
of the quarterbacks that signed, you
know, Gino Smith.
>> So,
>> you don't think Willis was ever crossed
your mind really either, huh? That that
was the one I thought is different than
all the rest.
>> Yeah, I mean, I think they evaluated it,
but I I never got the sense they were
going to be in on it. It was really
Miami Arizona for that one
>> was my sense all along. So, uh yeah,
it'll be interesting to see what the
Rams do because it looks like they'd
like to bring back either Garopolo or
maybe sign Kurt Cousins as a backup.
Whoever doesn't sign with the Rams,
they'll still be out there. You know,
does Pittsburgh just want to get a
>> maybe cousins to the Raiders?
>> Yeah, that's a good one. I mean, I do
think Well,
>> yeah, if we're playing dominoes, I know
the Raiders were in talks with Joe
Flacco before he signed with Cincinnati,
but they just couldn't come to an
agreement. So, he's like, "Well, forget
it. I'll just go play for Cincinnati
again." So, because of that, they can
pivot to Cousins. I I do think that
might be the play.
>> But, does Pittsburgh want to get
involved in one of those two guys is
just just to have an extra option? I
still don't sense they are doing that
>> which tells me that it's probably going
to be Rogers but we just don't have any
evidence of that yet.
>> Do you think Carr will be in the league
this year?
>> I don't
>> really.
>> You don't think there's enough people
banging down his door after you're off?
>> I think the window has passed especially
when you sit out a year.
>> You know, it was kind of a clumsy exit
in New Orleans with the injury and the
$30 million. I don't know. I I don't
sense teams are clamoring to sign him
now.
>> Okay,
>> Jeremy. Uh 22 days until the NFL draft
opens. of course on the north shore of
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Go ahead and
get in line for the tunnels now if
you're trying to make it on time.
>> Uh do you feel like with the sense that
it's not the strongest draft class and
particularly at the quarterback
position, we could see less movement, a
more static draft this year than than
typical years.
>> Possibly. It really depends on how you
view a Tai Simpson, for example. like
you know I've talked to teams who think
he could go in round one but it's it's
tough because you know not all teams
value him as a first round pick either
as far as a grade you know so does this
go the way of Shador Sanders where he
falls or does he become an option kind
of like Jackson Dart last year where he
was ascending more toward the draft then
you had the New York Giants come in in
the late first round to make a trade to
get him you know could you see somebody
do that so I still think he'll probably
go in the first somewhere but I don't I
think it'll be high. I think it be more
later. And yeah, outside of that, there
just aren't a lot of slam dunks. You
know, Garrett Nusmire, I still think
will be a day two pick somewhere. Um,
and if you go back to his 2024 tape was
pretty good, you know. So, uh, you know,
Drew Aller and at Penn State has a lot
of ability, but a lot of questions like
there just a lot of polarizing prospects
at that position that's going to be, uh,
more so for the mid rounds, you know,
mid to late rounds. just I I don't sense
a lot of movement outside of Mendoza at
one
>> in including the quarterback market, but
I think overall do you think it's safe
to say that the league is coveting picks
for next year's drafts more than this
year's draft?
>> It's it does seem
>> the Steelers can dump a third rounder
for a second rounder, second rounder
next year.
>> It might be harder to swing than you
think.
>> It does seem that way. It's funny. I
feel like I hear every year from other
teams like, "Oh, it's not a really
strong draft and they're only like 10 or
12 or 12 first round picks and next
year's draft is better." Yeah. I I feel
like that's the conversation a lot. And
this year's draft was supposed to be a
good quarterback draft if you ask people
eight months ago. Yep.
>> And then it wasn't. So, uh it's always
fluid and Yeah. But I do sense at least
from a quarterback position, they're
supposed to be
>> uh more more uh
>> more options at least.
>> Yeah. just
>> maybe a little more flare at the
position than you have this year.
>> Jeremy Fowler with us here on the drive
on Steelers Nation Radio, the Steelers
Audio Network. All right, Jeremy. One,
both or neither. Miles Garrett, AJ Brown
trades from their current organization.
One of those guys. Both of those guys.
Neither of those guys playing for a new
team in 26.
>> I'll say AJ Brown traded. Miles Garrett
stays. I mean, the Browns have been
pretty uh, you know, definitive, I
think, and that they're not trading
Miles Garrett. Maybe there's a little
wiggle room there or it's just hard to
believe because they're not a good team
and you figure he can go somewhere and
win, but
>> really cash in on him now. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Just I don't know. It doesn't It
doesn't make a lot of sense for them to
trade him. You know, he's clearing away
their best player. You know, he's still
good enough to help win games on his own
at times. And the Browns do, even though
they're in transition, they do expect to
be better offensively this year. So, it
doesn't make a lot of sense. AJ Brown,
that's been building for months. You
know, I've talked to people with other
teams back in October and November who
were sort of projecting that they would
have to trade him. And Howie Roseman's
message this week is, well, AJ Brown's
an eagle for now, and that's all I can
say. Well, a month ago, he was saying,
uh, you know, you don't want to trade
away really good players. Yep.
>> So, the the tune is different now.
>> Uh, where it seems like it's inevitable.
I would say just depends on when, you
know, but I I just I don't think he
wants to be there either. So, it just
makes sense to move on at this point.
>> Last thing I got for you is along those
lines, too. Is do we think Max Crosby is
now a Raider and not going anywhere?
>> Well, yes. I would say the draft is
always a time where things can heat up a
little bit. If we're talking about
timelines right now, it's sort of
dormant.
>> You know, late April, does somebody make
a move at him? Try to buy low on him a
little bit compared to what the Ravens
would have given up with the two first
round picks. I don't think the Raiders
want to do that at this point because
they know they can't get a great return
and it didn't work out. You have the
stigma of the knee issue, but then you
also have a really good player back in
your building. So, it seems like both
sides are willing to move forward with
each other for now and then, you know,
but
>> I wonder if it's like a trade deadline
thing. They, you know, the Lions call
them the trade deadline and, you know,
no, you can still have them.
>> Yeah. Like there there's a scenario that
is workable, right? If you go into the
season, he shows he's healthy, training
camp early in the year, playing really
well, five or six sacks.
>> Yeah, the knee is not an issue, then
maybe you do it at the deadline. I think
that probably makes the most sense.
>> One more for you before we let you go,
Jeremy. Uh what's your temperature
gauge, heat check on this uh this
standoff between the league and the NFL
referees association? Are we going to
have another uh replacement ref
scenario? Is it still just in the uh the
posturing and the kind of narrative
phase of this and you think something
will get done before the season? How
what's your confidence level on all
this,
>> man? Well, I think it is some posturing
going on. Yes. But, you know, the league
is prepared to hire replacement refs and
they're they're prepared to do it here
pretty soon. So, that does apply some
pressure. Uh it's complicated because
those guys I feel like take more
scrutiny now than they ever have.
>> Sure. So I think as a result they're
fighting for their rights a little
stronger, more fervently, you know, so
that's why it could take some time. It's
a concern. It's probably the biggest
concern here. You know, the league has
nudged people around it and inside it to
to not talk about this stuff and you
know, but that the the negotiations
haven't really gone anywhere. Usually
you'd like to see at least a little
progress by now. So I think that's the
biggest concern. So anything's on the
table with that? I mean, it feels
possible uh that you could have issues
here. And and really the bigger
conversation is, you know, the league
office in New York has their kind of
mothership now where they have a 100
cameras. They got this big control room.
>> They can start to make more calls.
They're going to vote this week on
>> whether they should be able to intercede
on like let's say something
unportsmanlike that happened. Yeah.
>> That they can identify and throw a flag
on from New York. So, it's going that
way and that that's looming large in
these discussions as well is how much
influence will New York continue to
have.
>> Great stuff as always. Jeremy Fowler,
you see him all over the place. Sports
Center, NFL Live, ESPN.com. I assume
you'll be you'll be in Pittsburgh here
in a few weeks for the draft, obviously.
>> I don't think I will. Actually, I'm
usually in Connecticut for the draft
just doing things locally. Um, I'd love
to though, man. I need to lobby for
that.
>> Get get back to your former stomping
grounds.
>> Yeah, man. It's going to be nuts.
>> It's going to be fun. Great atmosphere.
It
>> It sure it sure will. Well, it sure
will, Jeremy. Thanks for taking the
time, man. We appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Good afternoon, Steeler Nation, and
welcome back inside the Builtmore in
Phoenix, Arizona for our final day of
league meetings coverage here on the
drive. Wesler and Matt Williamson with
you. It's another bonus threehour show
and we are off and running. Matt, we are
rolling. Morning starting great.
>> We are on cloud9 right now for a let me
say a trio of different reasons. Okay.
>> So many.
>> F first of all,
>> I don't know how you narrow it down to
three. First of all, Mike McCarthy's uh
breakfast this morning. We have we have
the audio and and all the good
information and details from that that
we're going to actually play for you
here uh in just a few minutes. You and I
had a lovely time at the annual league
owners uh meeting dinner last night.
Some
>> pretty impressive affair.
>> Incredible, incredible food and who's
who of the football world.
>> Yes.
>> And then we finally here this morning
got our Nike swag bags, our giveaways.
We got a bag from Nike. We got a bag
from New Era. We got a bag from
Fanatics. I got a couple NFL hoodies for
my daughters. We got probably $2,000
worth of merch stuff.
>> I mean, just getting it on the plane is
is going to be a an adventure. You know,
the puzzle pieces to build the build it
>> and lovely breakfast. We get to do this
show. I wouldn't narrow it down to
three. And the weather is fine as could
be. It's going to be a big Steeler day
starting with coach McCarthy's
breakfast. I mean, we got a lot more AFC
and Steeler stuff to talk about and
>> and then uh back on a plane tomorrow.
>> Exactly. Right. It all happens very
fast, but it's been a lot of fun. And
yeah, that dinner last night was
certainly something by my estimation,
two sushi stations, two steak stations.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> There was salmon there.
>> Salmon and seafood and stuff, too.
>> Uh then there was a burger truck, there
was what am I forgetting? A pasta
station as well, too.
>> Yeah. Um, and about, you know, I think
four different open bars with a bunch of
different crazy cocktails and fun drinks
and all different kind.
>> A very classy band that was playing.
Yep. With a really good lead singer. Uh,
and it was so it was a lot of fun last
night. The NFL's uh who's who last night
there at the uh uh at the uh annual
league meeting owners uh dinner party.
>> Yeah. And kind of paint the scene. It's
pretty cool. like you go through the
resort a little bit and then you go and
and there's like a huge bar area with
all kinds of water features and that's
like the lower level. And as the night
went on, it seemed like a lot of the
more recognizable folks were down there,
you know, just doing their own thing. I
mean, no one's swinging from chandeliers
or anything, but I mean, they're having
a good time. And then, like you
mentioned, you go up to the next level
and it's almost everything on the right
is the same as everything on the left.
Okay. like start with sushi, start with,
you know, like everything parallels each
other. Big band in the middle, big area
in the middle,
>> like a big fancy wedding reception.
>> And then we went to the left and we were
calling that Kitty Land because there
was a lot of like things for kids. There
were ponies over there and that was
crazy.
>> You could make friendship bracelets and
and all and selfie stations, all that
different kind of stuff.
>> Yeah. And an amazing where we spent some
time was this particular bar area were
making smoked drinks. There was only
four drinks to pick from. One was an
espresso martini, which was not my bag.
You were doing some sort of tequila
smoked something.
>> Basically a watermelon smoked watermelon
margarita. It was in as refreshing of
you can imagine. Yeah.
>> And we were doing like smoked Manhattans
and you know Yeah. It was great. And I
didn't realize till the end you got to
pick which wood they would smoke with.
Did you catch that? Cherry or something
else? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm not sure I
could tell the difference, but hey, they
were going down good and we had a good
time.
>> They sure they sure did. We got some
customized bag tags that the NFL gave
out, too. Uh I got to talk with,
>> you know, maybe, you know, if you if you
list the uh distinguished WVU alumni. Uh
I think,
>> of course, your bag tag is WV.
>> I think Well, that's my initials. What
do you want me to do about it? I think
uh I slot in maybe at number two right
behind this Pat McAfee guy. I don't know
if you've heard of him, but he hosts a
national show on ESPN.
>> Yeah, you went and chatted with him a
little bit, right?
>> Talked to talked to McAfee a little bit.
We've got a bunch of mutual connections.
He's been on the the WVU show that I do
a few times. I do a show with one of his
former teammates, Owen Schmidt, who
played in the NFL for a few years for
the Eagles and the Seahawks and the
Raiders.
>> They were teammates, you said, right?
>> They were teammates at WV. Yeah. So, so
that was fun. Um
>> had to be a heck of a teammate. I I just
remember him as a draft prospect cuz he
was like a 265 Patrick Ricard fullback
type dude, you know? Absolutely. Mashing
face masks. So, yeah. So, we got to uh
we got to hang out with some of our our
friends in the Pittsburgh media. We got
to hang out with some people in the
national media. An incredible dinner. a
really cool site to see and then today
kind of being the um the cherry on top
of all this. You know,
>> this be our last show from here, but
>> in our in our last show from here, Mike
McCarthy lengthy head coaches media
availability today. It's a it's almost
like a
>> I don't want to say a breakfast setting
because it's not like everyone's eating
but it's in the morning. It's in the
morning around breakfast time and they
all sit in a ballroom around big, you
know, circular tables and everyone can
kind of local media, national media get
in there and ask a bunch of questions
and there is obviously a bunch that the
Steelers head coach Mike McCarthy had to
say there that we want to discuss
further.
>> And Matt, I think of course you have to
start at the top with all the latest on
Aaron Rodgers.
>> Yeah. Saying that he actually talked to
him last night. Uh that they've that
he's spoken with Aaron Rogers quote
every couple of days. uh they talk about
life, they talk about football, they
talk about what's going on at the
facility. I quote, "I would just say
he's in a very positive space. We'll
just continue to engage in our
conversations." He was also asked about
if he'd be comfortable with Aaron Rogers
missing OTAAS. Said he didn't want to
get into any hypotheticals. Quote, "I
truly understand why you're asking the
question. I'm just focused on my next
conversation with him." End quote.
>> Yeah. And that all sound, again, I don't
want to jump to conclusions, but that
sure sounds like there's a really good
chance Aaron Rogers is going to be the
starting quarterback. And the
communication
>> actually surprised me to the was to that
level, you know? I mean, we don't need
to narrow it down. We talk every two
days or whatever, you know, but I mean
it obviously they're in pretty constant
communication. And that's not even
mentioning how often Tom talks to him or
Cam Hayward even for that matter. I mean
they're friends. I mean that that they
could be talking about their kids or
whatever or Omar or whatever. Like I
don't think they're running by personnel
decisions like do you approve of Michael
Pitman, Aaron Rogers? You know, I don't
think that kind of stuff's happening.
But the um the constant communication I
thought really stood out because
there's obviously massive mutual
interest here.
>> Totally. And that's where this all
continues to go.
You know, we're not going to get an
answer until we get an answer. But all
the tea leaves uh continued to come up
that this is the uh
>> the future for the Pittsburgh Steelers.
We're a little distracted here because
Emil from video just brought over a
Gatorade can. Yeah,
>> canned Gatorade. That's
>> Look at this. I haven't seen one of
these, I don't think, since I was like
10.
>> That's rare right there. That's like
pulling a Barry Bonds rookie card.
That's the That's the That's the That's
the good stuff right there.
>> I'm going to have to try it. It's been a
while.
>> I'm going to have I'm going to need a
couple of those things. Gator Gatorade
out of a can is just hidden.
>> Might have to grab one for tomorrow
morning, too.
>> So, that was the uh that was the
biggest, you know, I mean, just in terms
of the general conversation, Matt. But,
you know, a couple things that also
really stood out to me, maybe the the
quote of the day.
>> Couple things did. Yeah.
>> Quote of the day from Mike McCarthy. You
got to love this when asked about Caleb
Johnson, who we've had that conversation
and how he fits into the Steelers
running back room and how you attack
that position group in the draft. Mike
McCarthy on the Steelers uh running back
who's heading into his sophomore season
with a lot of question marks. Quote, "I
am aware of their past experiences, but
this is like a Catholic operation. If
you say three Hail Marys, everybody has
a clean slate and let's get to work."
End quote.
>> Which I think is a great way to do it
from a new staff. I mean, obviously the
front office has a what what he put on
tape or didn't put on tape is still out
there. And you don't just throw away
what you think of the player just cuz a
new coaching staff comes in. If you you
question his pass blocking or his
cutting ability or whatever. I mean, you
still need to analyze the player as
impartially as possible without
question.
>> But you and I have been saying this for
a while. I mean really since the
coaching hiring that I feel like Roman
Wilson and Caleb Johnson are not
necessarily the happiest but sort of the
h career-wise the happiest of we get
some new eyes on us and I don't think it
was personal. We don't like these two
draft picks or whatever. It's just it
didn't work out. They didn't live up to
expectations yet. They're still young
and they get a kind of a new lease on
life and I'm glad McCarthy sees it that
way. And I'm glad you bring up Roman
Wilson because McCarthy uh said that he
recently had a great conversation with
Roman Wilson saying new system, fresh
start. I'm hoping he's one of those guys
that would benefit from it. I was
impressed talking football with him.
There's a lot of people that have a lot
of love for him in the building.
>> Good. Good. I mean, I I they're
obviously going to continue to address
that position, but to what degree might
tell us a little bit about what they
feel his chances of not necessarily even
making the team, but being a real
contributor are. You mean do they
envision him of maybe he is a number
three? Like I definitely think they're
going to take one in the top two rounds
or very very early, but is there at
least a story they could tell that
Wilson might be our three? You know, is
he competing with a second round pick in
a fifth round pick and the two of them
are going to
the four?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And battle it out or
situationally they'll be out there
differently. Who knows?
He was also uh obviously asked about how
they approach the quarterback position
in the draft and he said, "I'm hopeful
there will be a quarterback, you know,
at the right time there for us to
probably add to our roster." Um,
>> that was one of the things that really
stood out to me.
>> And he said, "The other part of that is,
okay, what's the ceiling? What's the
floor? Sometimes I get excited about the
floor." That kind of sounds like a
mid-round quarterback a little bit to
me, Matt Williamson.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I again I have mixed
feelings if I think that's the right
move or not. And I really could make
equally strong cases if I was the
prosecuting or defending attorney in
terms of should they take a third to
fifth round quarterback. And obviously a
lot of it has to do with who's available
and who it is. You don't just take one
to take one.
>> But what stood out to me what you didn't
mention there he said something along
the lines of I wish I had five
quarterbacks in my quarterback room
every year. I wish the NFL allowed that
to happen. And it kind of dawned on me
that would be probably good for the
league to be honest with you.
>> That's the development system that you
talk about.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. Maybe they could
make a, you know,
every team gets four quarterbacks no
matter what, you know,
>> and then somebody break the rules
>> exemption or salary exemption or
something.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Like they just
don't count against you get 50 a 50man
roster and four quarterbacks, you know,
something like that or whatever. And
would that be so terrible have a guy
hovering around for a year or two just
under Rogers and all the stuff he would
learn? Yeah.
>> You know, I'm sure someone would cheat
and put Taesm Hill in there and then
then make him into a tight end or
something, but whatever. You know, they
can legislate that.
>> And the last thing,
>> he just wants to work with more and more
young guys at that position, which is
kind of his specialty, you know.
>> And then the last thing, Matt, we got
about I don't know two or three minutes
here till we got to go to break, but I I
wanted to make sure to mention this. He
talked about pos one thing that really
stood out to me. I put like two stars
next to this on my notepad here.
>> He talked about how position flexibility
is so critical for offensive line. Yeah.
>> How how often how often do you uh start
and finish the year with the same five
offensive linemen? It's rare. You got to
move those guys around. You got to make
it work on a week-toeek basis.
>> That made my ears perk up because we've
talked a lot about the Steelers interest
in one of those offensive linemen that
has the potential to play guard and
tackle. Yes. you know, some of these
interior guys that can play all three
positions, guard, center, guard. I am uh
that made my ears perk up because I
think that's an even now that just
reinforces what we've talked about. A
real option for the Steelers at 21, at
53, you know, early in the draft, one of
those offensive linemen with versatility
and flexibility.
>> Yeah. And I don't want to look too much
into it, but the only offensive line
addition they made was Hoffman, right?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And and he could play
>> he could play all three. Yeah. Right.
It's not just because he played with
McCarthy, you know, in Dallas, I think
that position flexibility is absolutely
important in that conversation. Um, like
as much as I like Aone from Penn State,
>> that's my only thing I don't love about
the situation is if you plug him in at
guard, you'd probably never move him
anyway
>> cuz he'd be so good
>> because yeah, he's a guard and he's
really good at it, so you wouldn't move
anyways. but it doesn't influence your
left tackle problem at all or potential
upcoming problem
>> where some of these other guys, you
know, Proctor or
EHO or whoever have Yeah. I mean,
there's a lot of those guys
>> have a more of a guard
>> than maybe tackle path and that might be
a tiebreaker for me, but
>> Maui Go is like that, too. Now, he's
going to be drafted way way out of the
Steelers range, but there's a lot of
guys that
>> there's a lot of guys fit that mold,
right? and and I like that better, you
know, but if he's a great guard and you
never have to move him, that's a pretty
good problem now, too. Don't get me
wrong.
>> Um
>> if he's Allen Fanica, you'll take it.
>> Yes. Uh one other thing that did stand
out to me, I know we're up against it,
but every time I've heard him speak in a
public setting, he's very appreciative
and knowledgeable of those who came
before him here. And obviously him and
Tomlin over overlapped as head coaches
and they had a relationship. But he even
brought up like
>> chase each other in a Super Bowl.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, he even brought up
Austin and going back to Cower and Null
and I mean, he and it's not just because
he's from Pittsburgh. I mean, I think I
mean, I'm sure that helps, but I mean, I
think he realizes what was built here
and I'm going to keep it going. I'm not
going to change the course of this
train. You know, we're not, you know,
laying new tracks, going the opposite
direction. you know,
>> as a guy who's been the steward of
>> probably the three biggest NFL
franchises in the Steelers, the Cowboys,
and the Packers, I think he gets I think
he gets how important that lineage and
that history is when you're with
organizations like that.
>> I got a kick out even when when Rogers
signed, he talked about how,
>> you know, obviously there was Jets in
between and he didn't mention them. He's
like, "Now I've been a part of two of of
the big, you know, like people know that
stuff, especially the older folks that
have been around the league a long time
and appreciate it." Yeah, they sure do.
That's real. So, that's the kind of the
uh the Mike McCarthy hour here of the
drive to get us started today. Joining
us now, a familiar voice, a familiar
name, of course, the co-host of the
Steelers Blitz uh at noon on the
Steelers Audio Network with our guy Tom
Opperman. It is Chris Adansky. Also
covers the Steelers for the Trib. What's
up, Buzz? How we doing? You uh you
enjoying this Arizona sunshine?
>> It's a dry heat, I hear. Right. It's a
dry heat here.
>> It makes sense, though. I finally get
it. Like, Matt and I were talking about
this this morning.
>> The Uber driver today. Yeah. 90 degrees
here doesn't feel like 90 degrees.
>> Exactly right. Become a cliche and like
a joke, but it's actually true. Like you
come here, it was like 92 or something
yesterday, right? Warm,
>> but didn't feel like 92 in Pittsburgh is
a different 92.
>> Exactly right.
>> Our Uber driver was asking us where
we're from. You're from Pittsburgh. He's
like, "Yeah, I'm going up there in
August." And he was all worried about
he's like, "What's it?" The
>> guy lives like, "It's super humid up
there,
>> right? Like, what's the humidity like up
there?" I'm like,
>> "It's not like Florida and you know what
you hear about the south." But yeah,
it's I love this weather out here. Now,
I'm sure it's much different in June and
July and August when it's 115 degrees
outside, but man, I can't imagine many
places with better weather in March than
than here in Arizona. Certainly, it's
been it's been a welcome development
after the winter that we had back home.
>> Chris Adamsky, uh any difference in your
So, you were at the Mike McCarthy
breakfast this morning. Uh you've been
boots on the ground here for about 24
hours now. Do you feel any differently
about Aaron Rogers uh today than you did
maybe 24 hours ago or before you got to
Arizona? Where where are you at in this
whole ongoing uh conversation?
>> I'd say it's more just a re
reaffirmation uh more so I I I probably
felt that. I was going to say I do yes
probably feel more confident that that
that Aaron Rogers will be here or be
with the seniors is here at some point.
But I pro I probably felt that yesterday
you know two days ago too. So I don't
know how much it could have been more
reinfor but I guess reinforced I guess
is probably the the proper way to look
at it and
>> been a lot of communication it sounds
like.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's I mean you wouldn't
think I know they have a you know human
relationship not a coach and they've
known each other for 20 years or
whatever but I think they'd be talking
to each other on the phone every other
day as as Mike McCarthy's acknowledging
over and over again that they're they
talked last night after the after did
all the meetings and everything
yesterday. So I don't think you're doing
that.
>> They did that last year or the year
before.
>> Yeah, exactly. So I I there's there's a
obviously a purpose to it to I don't
think they're breaking down what they're
going to do on the second and three and
and you know in the first quarter of a
game, but I but I do think there you
know he said he's he's involved. What
was the word he used? Um immersed in
what's going on in the offseason. He's
keeping them so there's definitely a
degree of keeping things communication
there, keeping them posted where they're
at with everything. And uh yeah, I I
don't think it's ironclad. I don't I I
don't think it's like a there's a a
thought outside that there's this um
submersive like, oh, he's definitely
coming. We're not going to tell anybody.
I you know, I don't think it's that. I
don't think it's like, okay, keep this
quiet. But but I do think there's a
general feeling that uh this is going to
happen here at some point.
>> Yeah. And one thing Wes pointed out from
that interview, too, we just replayed it
last hour, was he mentioned versatility
amongst his offensive linemen, and we we
noted that Hoffman's the only guy that
they've added from outside the
organization. and he can play all three
interior spots. I certainly think
there's a really good chance maybe even
round one that they invest in a big-time
prospect on the O line, someone to play
on the left side. But do you think
versatility is going to factor in to
that equation?
>> He talked a lot, you're right, you you
listen to about that his philosophy in
general both and and I think that's
generally just modern football anymore
and true certainly in in defense and all
but in defense the secondary. I mean,
we're going to talk a lot, I'm sure you
guys are talking a lot about where's
Jaylen Ramsey go and all that. I I just
feel like that'll be down to down
>> uh game plan to game plan, week to week,
that type of thing where you know, there
might be games or situations where he's
playing, but that that's just what in
the offensive line part of that now
it's, you know, whether the Steelers
kind of had a, you know, say, they
weren't, it wasn't like we couldn't wait
for Samo to leave. It wasn't like kick
him out the door. Sometimes you get that
point with a veteran guy, no, we're not
resigning him. I think there there was
interest or or they wanted to have him
back or open having him back.
>> Um so it it would be sort of
disingenuous to say well they expect
Spencer Anderson to step in and play
right away whenever uh say a mother
could have been back and they obviously
bring in a a veteran free agent like
they have. But you're right I you know
if maybe a couple months ago I maybe
just me my blind spot I didn't think
offensive line was really a a a uh a big
possibility for the first round of the
draft. But the more and more this
process goes on, the more and more you
just hear more and more you kind of read
the tea leaves, the more you know, and
the Brick Jones thing. I think a couple
months ago, I don't think I was me
again, me didn't think would be a
physical question, a health question
mark at this point of the offseason as
we head into, you know, soon enough
here, get on the field. So, I think that
factors.
>> There was a little bit of news about I
wanted to follow up with you on that.
What are what are you hearing on Brick's
health?
>> Yeah,
I feel like
>> it's hard to get that information. Yeah,
it's
>> I I I don't I think medically wise I I
think there's the belief he's going to
be cleared to even by OTAAS and things
like like from a medical perspective,
but it's also like he he's an offensive
line. I mean, you need to you train your
body has been sort of, you know, neck
back type of thing here. We do your
offseason strength program, your
everything like that. It can't be done
really. So I think there is a little bit
of sort of like I don't think it's a
matter of he'll be out for the season or
anything like that but I think it's kind
of like okay where are we at with him
obviously then that isn't even I think
part of it if he was an allp pro left
tackle
>> then I was like well okay he'll be fine
by but you know if he had his off
seasonason being like this and kind of
not be able to do so I think they kind
of have to approaching it they kind of
have to hedge things and we can't really
we'll see how it plays out and hopefully
he he is back hopefully you know builds
up and you know gets physically where he
needs to be to be a starting lineman and
of Obviously then that's it's kind of a
separate issue, but it all goes together
the the performance and where he's at
and everything in terms of what we've
seen from him on tape here the first
three years of his career. You had a
good point though too. I mean it's such
a strengthbased position and I'm tr sure
this is true to some degree with almost
every injury but back and neck I'm sure
he's not benching or doing rows or I
mean anything close to upper body maybe
not even lifting at all during this
stretch. I mean he has to lose some
strength during this whole process.
Yeah, you're right because that
obviously the core in the back and
there's so many I mean I guess you could
do legs I guess and theoretically it
wouldn't be but you but just and we're
talking about an NFL offensive tackle. I
mean that's something that people kind
of have injuries. I get it but I just
think all the questions around it um in
terms of where he's at and physically
and just the neck in general type of
thing. It it it doesn't sound at all
like it's anything like not that they're
different players and I don't think
anybody really believe this but when you
start getting to the point where it's
neck and things like last year was a
player and I skipped my name right now
that the defensive watch. Yes. Yes. And
he had to retire me. I don't they're not
anywhere to that level that degree or
anything but now it's just a point of
>> he can be physically cleared and then
it's like building building himself back
up. So, it's still, you know, as we sit
here right now at this moment, it's
still March. Just April's coming real
soon here. And we're starting to build
up toward where it will does get too
late. Um, or it gets late. It's still
still early yet. So, I think it'll be
okay. But, um, yeah, I don't I don't I I
think they're happy with where medical
wise in terms of getting cleared that
kind of I don't think there's anything a
doctor said, "No, he can't do, you
know."
>> You don't think they pick up his fifth
year option, though, do you? I I
really'd be shocked. Yeah, I'd be Yeah,
I I
>> if he was a better player or 100%
healthy, but two strikes against you,
it's like
>> Yeah, it's really
>> And Cook's not bad, you know.
>> Exactly. You have Cook and if we're
sitting here talking and I and I agree
with you that first round tackle is a
possibility, right? I mean,
>> not only if that h if that happens, it
even slams the door even more on on the
first on the fifth year option for for
Jones. But the fact that's even in play,
I pretty much possibility. Yeah, it it
says kind of where things are at.
>> And it looks like there'll be guys to
pick from at 21 at tackle. Some years
you can't even go down that road. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Chris Adamsky, co-host of the Steelers
Blitz, covers the Steelers for the Trip
with us here on our mini radio row
inside the Builtmore in Phoenix,
Arizona. Uh Chris,
>> we're doing a lot of heavy lifting on
radio row this year.
>> We are Texans have not held up their
side.
>> We are uh we're about onethird of the
radio representation down here.
>> Oh, I think we're about 90% of the radio
representation.
>> We're the uh we're the Aaron Rogers in
this in this room down here. you know,
we're the ones walking right into Canton
one day and everyone else is just on the
coattails. Uh, speaking of quarterbacks
buzz, uh, there continues to be a lot of
positive buzz from Mike McCarthy and
company on Will Howard. Uh, Mike
McCarthy saying that if he was in charge
of the draft last year, Will Howard
would not have lasted into the sixth
round? I I is this is this real? How
much of a crack is he going to get? Do
they really feel like at least maybe by
the time we get out of Latroe, he can be
the clear-cut number two?
Yeah, there's I I do believe that
there's genuine um curiosity. There's
genuine admiration from afar from the
from the coaching staff that came in.
Mike McCarthy, remember he did talk he
took the he said he and he said that and
he talked about watching Will I mean
Will Howard I always talk about he was
the arguably he wasn't but the highest
he was the starting quarterback on the
national championship team. So he got
more airtime than any college football
player in the country two years ago. Um
so everybody kind of knew who he was and
and kind of followed him. So, and I
think there was that admiration seeing
how well he played during that that
stretch. And whenever you're at the at
that point during that college football
playoff run by Will Howard last year,
that stretch right when Mike McCarthy
had been let go or left or parted ways,
I should say, with the Cowboys, everyone
put it. So, he he was watching more
football at that point than he had. So,
he saw like peak Will Howard tape at
that. He's watching it live in terms of
of what what he's doing. So, I I do
believe that it's genuine for sure that
that the that the offensive staff and
and Mike in particular um like Will
Howard, but but I also don't there
there's something to say he's we like
him better than a six round pick to say
he's going to have to be a franchise
quarterback, right? I mean, so yeah, but
so but I guess the way Wes even talked
about the frame of the question. Yes, I
I do think there's certainly a
possibility that there's a scenario
where he he could be the number two this
as soon as this year. But
>> there's also the possibility that, you
know, you add the veteran, assuming it's
Rogers, and then they draft a
quarterback in the, you know, in the mid
rounds or whatever, and you're not going
to cut him, then then all of a sudden, I
don't want to say he'll get cut, but all
of a sudden it gets a little hairy, you
know, where he's at all in the depth
chart. Right. That's what I was going to
ask you next is because I've said this
eight million times that I understand a
case for and against a third, fourth,
fifth round quarterback and some I like
better than others. Some they'll like
better than others and they have to be
the right guy available. But that
probably is the writing on the wall for
Rudolph if you take him. I am always in
favor of taking a bite at the apple. You
might get a cheap, you know, home run
party situation, Dak Prescott situation.
He wants to work with young
quarterbacks. Stephen said, "I wish I
had five in my room this year."
>> Do you think they do it and would you do
it?
>> Yeah. I mean, I Well, Mark, well,
there's there's at least one other
person who's a bigger Will or Mason
Rudolph fan amongst the media than than
I am, but I've been always proponent of
of Mason Rudolph, but uh
>> and that's not a knock on Rudolph. It's
just they're not going to keep four.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And and
>> he's only contract one more year.
>> And I totally agree with you. you laid
out the reasons why taking a a mid round
quarterback because that you go into the
process you think okay if if they fall
in love with Ty or if they still do I
shouldn't use the past if Tai Simpson if
they that's something you don't pass up
you don't worry about
>> that's a different if you you think you
have a franchise guy in the first round
you're taking the pick everything else
is is you know secondary you worry about
that later but if you start going into
the mid rounds there all of a sudden you
know no one that you one way or another
they'll have Rogers or if there's
somebody else but if there's Rogers and
then there's Um, and yeah, you have
three guys going to make the team.
>> Yeah. And and so then you only three at
at the, you know, are going to make the
team. So
>> you have to look at it. That's that says
something about somebody, right? If you
take it in the mid rounds, you would
think or at least it spells trouble for
some it's Rudolph or right some because
all four of them can't make the team.
Now
>> Rudolph might flip him into a six round
pick or something to a team that needs
them or got team that gets injured, you
know,
>> and and that's what what I think is it's
a little bit interesting is um
Just watching Ben Roththersburg over the
final eight or nine years of his career
at training camp. He did the thing where
full practice, half practice, no
practice. And at least the first year
for Aaron Rogers, maybe because it was a
new team, maybe. I don't know. I was
surprised. I assumed at age 41 last
year, we wouldn't see him very much of
the truth.
>> We only missed two practices the whole
year, right?
>> Yeah. He was out there reps to go around
for all these young guys.
>> So, part of me thinks like they'll roll
the ball out there and and you know, do
the oldfashioned like, okay, Will, you
know, show us not, you know, you deserve
to be part of the future. Okay, Mason,
show us you you deserve to be part of
this team now.
>> And if you threw me in there, that makes
it all of a sudden there's not that many
reps to go around.
>> Exactly. So, it's a little bit harder.
Yeah. If you're trying to get your
starter prepared for the season. So,
that isn't ideal, but I mean, I do
Especially when you have 12 draft picks,
Matt. Your your idea would take a bite
at the apple. Yeah. It's a lot more
tenable. You almost I don't say you have
to.
>> Then you have to have a plan in place.
How do I get these guys developed?
>> But it's like it's almost harder to make
12 picks and not take a quarterback,
right, if you're in the situation. So,
it's almost like you kind of you'd
almost be waiting because you you take
12 picks at other positions and it's
another it's hard for those 12 guys to
make the team as it is. Now, you throw
an extra guy in there at a position that
it's going to be hard to make the team
>> that you want need to spend time
developing a fourth round quarterback.
He's to make the team.
>> Yes.
>> Couple more minutes here with our buddy
Chris Adamsky. Uh Chris, I wanted to ask
you just, you know, maybe uh kind of a a
national thing or two as it relates to
these uh these league meetings here.
What's your I guess on a scale of calm,
concerned, worried, and panicked. Okay.
Where are you at on the uh on the NFL
referees association in this stalemate
with the league?
>> Um I I mean I'm generally calmed and
concerned. I I guess I don't know. I
It's get up a lot brought up now a lot
the uh the fail Mary and things. I get
maybe after selective memory where it
wasn't. So I'm like, "Oh, you know,
it'll work it there's labor dispute will
work itself out. even if they start the
season, play a few weeks, then you know,
then the negotiation will come together.
But I guess you're right that if a
high-profile um mistake is made, if some
that that's what ended the uh the
dispute last time, what 13 years ago, 14
years ago now, when that happened is a
high highprofile gaff. So you hope that
you know if you're the Steelers, you're
not the one that happens to me. Maybe
you'll benefit from it though. Oh, this
is actually the best.
>> Yeah, this is great.
>> Um but you know, and again, just like I
said, there's lots of time. We talk
about Roger Jones. We're still it still
marched as we see here today. there's
not a a game of consequence for four and
a half months or over four month or five
months I I should say and even
exhibition games aren't for over four
months. So I think there's still plenty
of time and you know these negotiations
it's things it's you know there's a
little rhetoric going out the last
couple days but that's just part of the
part of the process
>> trying to win the narrative. Right.
>> Exactly. So I I I think that if if we're
still here and it's August August 1
instead of uh you know April 1 about to
hear then maybe the the level rises but
I think it'll be all right. Last thing I
have for you, and I I think we all
agree,
Roman Wilson, Caleb Johnson haven't
lived up to their draft expectations
obviously, but just listening to
McCarthy, and it's something I've kind
of inferred to this point,
>> they're going to get somewhat of a new
lease on life, don't you think?
>> Yeah. I mean, those two are probably the
two of the that I don't say happy about
the coaching change, but
>> that's the same words I use. I mean, at
least it's new eyeballs looking, right?
There's a clean slate aspect anytime
there's a a new coach that comes and
whatever you know the and and the the
staff that drafted and I mean the
coaching staff and I know they hated
Mike Tom influence obviously but they're
still on hand here. There was things
that they the Steelers liked about those
two players. They took the third round.
So, you still have that kind of support
behind you and you have a new set of
eyes. Now, just by so far what they've
done, the Steelers um free agency wise
and there's a long way to go with the
draft and everything and that could flip
on its head. But they haven't been as I
mean Michael Pitman that's aggressive
and it was the first moments of free
agency essentially, but aside from that,
the res been kind of quiet at wide
receiver and when you go out and
obviously more receivers play, more
receivers are part of your game day
roster, blah blah blah. Um, so but as we
stand right now, Roman Wilson is
probably still, you know, a starting re
as as the depth chart said to play
tomorrow. Exactly. Exactly. I don't
expect that to be the case, but I think
that is a little bit of an indication
that he's maybe in higher st because
it's going to be
>> Caitlin better whether he figures out
the kickoff return thing, gets back in
good graces with that or whether he
figures out another role on special
teams because right now the number three
running back,
>> you got to play teams. You have to play
teams.
>> So if he doesn't do that, that's when it
start. how he's still only a second
year. It's a lot more feasible to to
move on from somebody into in a third
year when you're a third round pick than
a second year. It's pretty rare. I don't
know. How often does a third round pick
cut before his second season starts?
>> Not very. But he was also drafted for a
different system. And maybe there's a
team out there that had a really high
grade on him one year ago. And I mean,
you wouldn't get close to your
investment. You might get a six round
pick back or return. But
>> and I still think again, if you have 12
picks, they might draft a running back
still. I mean, even with the homer.
>> Oh, you're definitely right. You know,
and then all of a sudden it gets real
tight.
>> Yeah, you're right. That's an excellent
point. That's an excellent point. And
just again, it's a teles hate to read
too much into we all hang on everywhere
at this point, but
>> both with um the general manager and the
coach McCarthy and and Omar so far. If I
feel like the answers are more
enthusiastic about a Roman Wilson than
they are about Caleb Johnson.
>> Yeah, I I got those vibes, too. Plus,
there's more roster spots to go around.
Yes. You know, right?
>> Yeah. So there's a lot there's a lot of
reasons why Roman seems a little in a
better spot right now. Yes.
>> Then Roman does have to run down on
kickoffs to save his job.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> We are in a better spot after having
about 18 minutes with our friend Chris
Adamsky. Make sure you're checking out
all his work in the trip this week and
of course listening to him and Tom here
on the Steelers Blitz on the Steelers
Audio Network. Buzz, thanks for the
time. Go Mars Planets.
>> There you go. MS Mars Mars.
>> Our third day at the league meetings. It
is the drive on location about 2,000
miles away from our studios in
Bridgeville, Pennsylvania, here in
Phoenix, Arizona, where it's sunny,
where it's beautiful, all the moving and
shaking of the annual league meetings.
And Matt, across the timeline here, via
Tom Pelisero, of course, of the NFL
Network. Uh, the NFL owners have
approved four rule changes.
>> Okay,
>> so here's here's what they are.
>> Get these things happen while we're
here, too. Yeah, right. There's a reason
everybody gets together.
>> I thought it was for the fancy dinner
last night.
>> Right. steak and the sushi and the
smoked watermelon margarita
>> and the Mexican floating around down
here and all that good stuff, too.
>> I'm about to I'm about to I'm about to
just abuse a burrito later for dinner. I
can't wait.
>> I think that's a good move.
>> Tom Pelisero saying, "These four have
passed." The first um to permit the
kicking team to declare an on-site kick
at any time during the game. Has passed.
>> Boom. I mean, I thought that was an easy
one.
>> And I still 97% of them will still be in
the fourth quarter.
>> Of course,
>> 98% of them will still be in the fourth
quarter. But if someone's shooting the
four first doesn't make it smart, but do
it. Who cares, right?
>> If you're down 17 points at the end of
the third quarter,
>> yeah, go for it.
>> Desperate times, you know. Right. Right.
Right.
>> Desperate times, desperate measures, all
that good stuff. Yeah. That
>> I think they just screwed that up when
they wrote it the first time.
>> Same.
>> You know, let's just correct it a year
or two later.
>> And that's how a lot of these things
work.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> That's why you have competition
committees, right? Uh, the second thing
that has passed here in Arizona is
eliminating the kicking team's incentive
to intentionally kick the ball out of
bounds when kicking off from the 50 yard
line.
>> That was a total loophole.
>> That was one of
>> I just think they just didn't think
through.
>> Yep. Special teams, how could you? Yeah,
it was the first time going through it.
>> Um, and so yeah, we saw that. Danny
Smith did that a couple times last year.
Uh, we saw it I remember in Dublin was
one of the times.
>> Yeah. Yeah. um
>> drill it out of bounds and
>> drill out of bounds and you end up
getting five yard you give the offense
five yards less of uh you know of field
of field position in the process too.
>> Kind of a helpless feeling if you're the
return team.
>> Yes. So that one uh certainly a little
bit of a loophole. Uh
>> so how did they word it? You're not
allowed to drill it out of bounds.
>> Yes. Now so again I think by accident
they probably still have to decide the
parameters on that. Maybe
>> I guess there's a big penalty. Maybe
it's a big penalty or it's just if you
kick it out of bounds, the ball goes
here.
>> You know, it's just it's just,
you know, it's at the 35 or it's
probably what it is, right?
>> Or whatever. So, some of the language of
these rules will still have to be um
delegated,
but but we know at least that
>> but what was proposed passed.
>> Yes. To eliminate that incentive to
intentionally kick the ball out of
bounds has passed. So, that's two of the
four. And um a third one also directly
we we talked about this on Sunday on our
kind of opening uh show and our our kind
of primer and 411 to set the scene here
for for the week. Um a lot of this
related
>> 411 mean
>> 411 is like need it's like your
information like 411
>> well I know but like what's why did that
come about?
>> That's a good question.
>> Why isn't a 287?
>> It's 411 relevant information or the
truth. What does the slang term 411
mean? Where did it derive from? I guess
is my
>> originates from the United States
telephone system where 411 was the
number dialed for directory assistance
to get information.
>> So it's like 911, you know, like there's
certain numbers you tell me.
>> It was Google basically before Google.
You dial 411, you could get your
information. Uh so give me the 411 is
all the news, all the all the gossip,
all the lowdown
>> way before internet and what
>> on a on a particular subject.
>> Yeah, I understood what it meant. I just
didn't know where it came from.
>> Hey, we're learning something new here
every day. A lot of these, as we shared
with you, are related to the kickoffs in
the third rule change that has passed is
also related to kickoff to modify the
kickoff alignment requirements for the
receiving team players in the setup
zone.
>> So, they're allowing that.
>> They're allowing that so teams will have
a little more wiggle room, a little more
freedom to how they want to uh align on
kickoffs. Now, it's not rigid and set
and static and has to be this way.
>> Again, that's both we both leaned that
way whenever we brought this stuff up,
you know, when we got here. And again, I
mean, like, if you're going to allow
defense coordinators, offense
coordinators, play designers on those
sides of the ball to be more creative
with their formations and schemes, why
not let the special team coaches do it,
too?
>> It makes a ton of sense.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> absolutely. Makes a ton of sense. So,
those three, I think we thought that
there was a really good chance that
those three would pass. All related to
>> I bet there wasn't much resistance on
those.
>> All related to the kickoff, all of those
proposed by the competition committee.
Uh, and according to Tom Pelisero,
>> you need to remember the whole dynamic
kickoff still pretty new.
>> It's we're only going into year three
here. So, we're the dynamic kickoff is
still on its rookie deal. Entering his
rookie deal, right? Three.
>> Looks like they'll pick up a fifth year
option, though, right?
>> I don't think it's going anywhere. I
don't think they'll have to think about
that one too much. And then finally,
Matt, the fourth and final rule change
uh that has passed according to Tom
Pelisero of the NFL Network is that
for one year only, the NFL will allow
the officiating department to correct
clear and obvious misses made by onfield
officials that impact the game. In the
event that there is a work stoppage
involving the game officials, uh
represented by the NFL referees
association.
>> Yeah. And at a minimum, this ref thing
is not going to go away soon. I'm sure
we'll be talking about this for weeks,
maybe months, hopefully not months and
months and months. Um, my takeaway, and
this really reaffirms it, is at a
minimum, the owners in the league are
putting pressure on the refs.
>> Yes. And that's all that it all. Right.
Right. Right.
>> But that's at least that much.
>> Yes.
>> They're they're they're push pushing the
hammer down a little bit. Oh, and also
uh via Pelisero, NFL owners also just
approved an amended rule change that not
only will allow league personnel to
consult with onfield officials when
considering disqualifications. Remember
we talked about this?
>> Yeah. Like spitting incidents and things
like that,
>> spitting and punching and stamping.
>> Um so not only uh to review those type
of things uh but also to uh throw a flag
on the play as well too. So not only
>> that did get approved.
>> Yes. Okay. So, not only could someone
from the league office or from the
booth, you know, buzz down and say,
"Hey, uh, Jamar Chase just spit on
Jaylen Ramsay." You got you got to eject
him out. You could also say you could
throw a 15 yard personal foul on that
even if the referees miss it all.
>> Good. Um, again, I think I brought this
up two days ago that
>> that should happen. I don't want people
getting away with disgusting acts and
things like that.
>> Yeah, I agree.
>> But how far do we take it? You know, is
it like
>> a shove?
>> Yeah. Right. Right. Right. Oh, he might
have hit him in the face mask after the
penalty.
>> Slight little palm to the face or does
it have to be a groin punch? Does it
have to be a stomp on the ankle? Does it
have to be putting your hand around
somebody's throat? You know, like
>> that does leave some interpretation up
to the officials.
>> I'm not super worried about it, but I
don't want someone to take it too far.
Like, we're going to review that. Come
on. You know,
>> that's where I'm with you. I obviously I
want technology to be part of the game,
>> but I don't want it to take over the
game.
>> Yes.
>> I think that's the balance. kind of like
in the Chase situation, it would have
absolutely changed the game, you know,
right?
>> I said this to you a few days ago. I I
think there there's not a lot that uh
that sports fans across the board all
agree upon, but I don't care if it's
football, baseball, basketball, hockey.
I think everybody wants technology to be
a part of the game. Yeah. They just
don't want it to take over and and clunk
up the the flow of the game at the same
time. There's a balance there that we're
all looking to strike.
>> Yes,
>> Matt. Couple more uh teased to cross and
eyes to dot before we put a bow here on
hour number two. The Super Bowl is
officially returning to Las Vegas in
2029.
>> Okay.
>> Oh boy, that'll be that'll be a fun
scene. Think many people want to go.
>> I think that'll be a fun scene there in
Las Vegas. Also, don't tell anybody I
told you this. All right. But I was
listening to some little birdies chirp
last night at the uh at the dinner.
>> Yeah.
>> Sounds like Nashville in 2030, which oh
boy,
>> that wouldn't be a bad spot either.
>> That would not be a bad spot, but my
goodness, downtown Nashville is like
smaller than downtown Pittsburgh. And
>> wow,
>> that would be a lot of fun, but a lot of
chaos. Uh but we
>> when the Steelers are there back to
back, you and I have a good time in
Vegas and Nashville.
>> Yes, exactly. We We sure will. We'll be
Listen, when we're uh when we're on the
NFL's diamond travel schedule, it won't
be a problem. We'll be we'll be we'll be
doing fantastic. Uh also announced by
the Minnesota Vikings, they are picking
up the fifth year option on wide
receiver Jordan Addison.
>> I thought that was semi-debatable. You
know, like Naylor was up for free
agency. I thought they might try to just
keep him and let Addison go. Um,
Addison's a good player. He's a really
good number two, but he's very small.
And I think he's a slightly overrated
player that benefits so much from
Jefferson being on the other side.
>> And he keeps getting in trouble.
>> I mean, he just keeps getting in trouble
over and over and over. Now, fifth year
option for a guy like him, he's probably
not going to a Pro Bowl. Isn't really
real dis.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> And I do think the Vikings are in it to
win it this year with Kyler. I mean, I
don't think they're taking a step back
and trying to rebuild or anything, but I
didn't know if this was a slam dunk.
>> Yeah, I didn't either. I mean,
>> he's always in trouble.
>> That's That's the kicker. He's a good
number two, and you know, you used a
first round pick on him a few years ago.
>> Um, but
>> but the fifth year option is also
different than I'm going to give you a
huge contract with a $25 million signing
>> and as you mentioned, especially if he
he was he was a later first round pick
if he hasn't hit a lot of those in
>> I don't think he's hit a lot of the
kickers. Yeah,
>> the number probably isn't crazy. It's
probably a fair number to pay a number
two wide receiver.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And maybe end up if it if he walks if he
walks the line like Johnny Cash, maybe
you end up extending him. If not, hey,
>> if he leaves at the end of the year, you
probably get a comp pick out of it, you
know.
>> Yeah. Exact. That's a good point, too.
Uh let's see here. Matt Dolphins GM John
Eric Sullivan shut down uh any potential
conversation regarding trade rumors for
Devon Achain earlier this morning. Uh
saying
>> I keep hearing that, but I don't know if
I believe it. saying that it's a
priority for them to extend him and
there's zero effort to move him.
>> Okay. I mean, originally when he said
that a couple weeks ago, right after the
Waddle trade, I just thought, man, no
one's offered enough yet. His style, I
mean, running backs just don't last in
this league, especially tiny ones. By
the time you're good, is is that a good
investment?
>> I don't know. I don't think
>> I mean, he certainly helps with
evaluating Willis, which is super
important. That part is important,
right? I mean, swing passes to him and,
you know, sort of competitive.
>> You got to have somebody that can do
something for you on that offense.
>> And they'll probably draft two good pass
catcher or young pass catchers, you
know, pretty high. But still,
>> yeah, I would think that's a piece you
want to move.
>> Then one of the last things that uh that
I think we need to discuss here, Matt,
because it's not a huge story now, but I
think in the coming years it will be,
and that is that the NFL announced a
partnership with Tomorrow Sports, the
company behind, you know, that uh Total
Golf League that we've seen on ESPN.
Sometimes it's all the pro golfers that
are in the indoor facility and they play
a virtual golf and the greens all
change.
>> Yes. Rory Mroy does it. Tiger Woods does
it. Like they've got big names.
>> We were in Indianapolis was the first
time I ever saw it. Right.
>> It's the same company that does that. Uh
they are developing a professional flag
football league for both men and women
that will be backed by all 32 NFL teams.
So the NFL partnering with Tomorrow
Sports for a pro flag football league.
Matt, the reason why I think right now
this doesn't grab a bunch of headlines
or move the needle, but it will
eventually is because remember a little
over two years from now, summer of 2028,
the summer Olympics are in Los Angeles
here in the United States and flag
football is going to be for the first
time an Olympic sport.
>> So, this I think is the ramp up to that
of
>> get used to it. have get people used to
it, get people interested in it, get NFL
players involved to see exactly what
that looks like because they are vastly
different games that are governed
differently and played differently.
>> But that I just think is important. I
think that's something that again today
isn't going to grab a bunch of
headlines, but I think this is the start
of potentially something that could be
substantial in in a couple years.
>> Yeah. And there was a a get together
here where um Larry was involved. Larry
Fitzgerald was involved.
>> That's right. We ran into your old
buddy. That's one of the things in all
the fun of yesterday. We forgot forgot
about that, right?
>> That was yesterday, right? Or was that
two days ago? Everything kind of blended
together. But yeah, he was here
promoting that with some other people
and I guess it went well. I didn't sit
in there, but I did run into Larry
before we we you know,
>> I thought I thought you would maybe
talk, you know, I'd heard from you for a
long time how good how good buddies you
are with Larry Fitzgerald and all this.
>> We don't I don't I don't see him or talk
to him on him and my wife him and my
wife used to get along and we used to
watch film together and I'm like, "All
right, let's see how how well Larry
remembers Matt. didn't know how well I'd
be received. Right.
>> We're walking down the hallway and we're
maybe 20 yards away from him and Larry
sees Matt and he starts smiling and
waving right away. All right. So, he
wasn't lying. He wasn't exaggerating.
They are they are buddies.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> He was happy to see you. And I think
everybody on Twitter and social media
got a kick out of how you're the same
height as Larry Fitzgerald. Everyone was
like, "Wow, how tall is Matt?"
>> That that was kind of odd because the
picture you took the pictures and I look
a lot taller than him or noticeably
taller than him and I'm not. And so like
a nerd, I looked up Larry Fitzgerald
combine measurements.
>> Yep.
>> And he was 6027, which is 62 and 78. So
just a shade under 63,
>> which is exactly what I am. And I'm
like, there's no way. I mean that I look
people were like, that looks like he's
6'5. I didn't realize what a giant. I'm
not 6'5. Yeah. It's just a weird
picture, I guess, or whatever. Yeah.
>> 63 in shoes.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> I think my hair was standing up from
wearing a headset all day, too. Right.
Before we go, you were always looking,
you were always looking tiptop there,
Matt Williamson.
>> Oh, but also flag. I want to mention I
love that women get to be involved. It's
a great sport. I mean, yeah. I mean,
I don't know if one day they'll wear
helmets and pads and play this version
of football or not, but it's great that
they, you know, a whole new realm of
young women and people are going to be
exposed to this in a in a professional
manner, you know.
>> It's great. Uh last thing before we get
to break and uh and to our buddy Allan
Saunders of Steelers Now to kick off our
bonus third hour. I've been keeping an
eye on this all day, Matt, because
remember Gerard McCoy, cornerback out of
Tennessee.
>> Oh, that's one of the more intriguing
prospects. Pro day in Knoxville in
Tennessee uh just within the past hour.
He just ran a 4.3840.
>> Oh, good for
>> 38 inch vertical jump. Okay.
>> And a 107 broad jump about a half an
hour ago at his pro game. more than just
checking the boxes of your healthy
>> first round pick.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I mean, he probably always was going to
be a firstrounder, but maybe now in the
in the top 10, top 15.
>> Yeah. I originally thought maybe he goes
to a bad team, you know, like the Jets
that can just wait on him and be the
eventual sauce replacement at like 17 or
whatever that is. Now, does he challenge
Delane to be cornerback one?
>> He just might.
>> I mean, I think it's not crazy.
>> He just might. Good day. Uh good day for
Jam McCoy for sure. It's been a good day
for us so far. Bonus hour, final hour
here of the drive on location inside the
Builtmore in Phoenix, Arizona for the
2026 NFL League owners meetings. And
joining us now to kick off our final
hour, he's been a guest few times here
in the last few months on the drive,
it's our buddy Alan Saunders, of course,
of Steelers Now. Allan, uh, this is my
first owners meeting. I have been
pleasantly surprised. This is a fabulous
event. And how have things been on your
end?
>> It's wonderful every year. I think this
is the best location. I love it here.
>> You like it better in Florida?
>> Yeah, I do. Uh it doesn't rain here. Uh
that's a good point.
>> It's um
>> it is hot. It it the got off the plane
and it's just like who turned the the
furnace on? Like gee, this is the night
and everything that way too.
>> Still hot. But I uh I think this is a
great setup here and uh they take great
care of us and yeah, really nothing to
complain about this week.
>> Have a good time last night. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's hard not to.
>> So, let's get right into it with you
here, Allan. And, uh, I know we kind of
had some some news in the the last half
an hour or so, but, the NFL owners
approving a rule change allowing the
league to step in and assist on
potential disqualifications, whether for
flagrant football acts or non-Os, and
initiate a flag if one wasn't thrown.
Uh, was the DK Metaf incident in Detroit
last year a real catalyst of this
conversation? I think it was uh it
certainly is the example case for how
the NFL would like this to play out
differently and honestly I think you
know when when we saw the suspension
handed out last year as two games and
then DK went to the appeal I thought ah
you know they'll probably knock it down
to one
>> and I think um you know maybe if he had
been ejected at halftime of that game
instead of playing the second half that
might have been something that happened.
So, I think in some ways,
you know, I I don't love the idea of of
the the flag from the from the press
box, right? From from then New York
clunky New York throws the flag on the
play.
>> I I think that's that's a little bit
fraught, but I think it will end up
helping resolve situ like it's such a
weird unique situation. I just hope they
don't overuse it. Like how many times
>> has a situation like that occurred where
>> you know you're sitting there watching
something happen I really probably
should be thrown out for that and and
and the officials didn't see it like it
it doesn't happen very often.
>> Were there any shocks of the things that
got voted? I mean I thought all the
kickoff stuff was pretty much cut and
dry easy decisions.
>> Yeah. Uh, I'm interested to see. I felt
like this this kickoff they were very
conservative with the roll out of the
the new kickoff where I think we're
going to see as they continue to tweak
this, we're seeing more returns.
>> Certainly, that's what they want. Yeah,
>> we're seeing more returns. It's a play
that exists again,
>> but we're not seeing anywhere near the
explosive plays that we saw at the
height of the kick return in the in the
early 2000s. I think I wrote there were
uh a handful of touchdowns last year. I
think that maybe maybe six. I think
>> uh there were in 2007 there were two
guys that had three.
>> Wow.
>> The whole league had six.
>> So it's like
>> they got to find
>> Dante Hall Deon Hester.
>> They got to find some ways to give the
return team a chance to make a big play.
And so giving them more flexibility in
where they line the guys up, I think is
what they're going for. the other I mean
the other the rest of it just seems very
cut and dry
>> pretty obvious stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> So like an underrated need I think that
I've been talking about for months and
even before this Steelers really could
use return guys
>> both punt and kick.
>> Yeah. They don't really punt. I mean
Jaylen Warren I assume will continue to
be one of the two guys back there on
kickoff return probably but uh Kenny
Gainwell was there you know. Um, uh,
yeah, I think and Mike McCarthy was
talking yesterday about he wants wide
receivers that can do more than one
thing. And he he very specifically said,
yeah, that could mean playing in the
slot or playing outside. It could also
mean go play on special teams and
>> return gunner.
>> They don't have a lot of bodies in the
wide receiver room. So, I think it makes
sense if you're looking at mid-round
picks, say, "Oh, go get another wide
receiver who can return some kicks."
Mhm.
>> Well, if you're kind of trying to read
the tea leaves of of the draft here in
what 23 days, it it kicks off in
Pittsburgh.
Uh Mike McCarthy spent some time this
morning talking about the value of
position flexibility, particularly how
critical it is for an offensive line.
There are a lot of those uh uh you know,
first round type prospects in this draft
and even some into the second round that
kind of profile as they could play guard
or tackle in the league. Does that kind
of does that put an antenna up? Does
that feel like a real option for the
Steelers to go back to the offensive
line at 21 even when they've invested a
lot of draft capital there recently?
>> I don't know that I see the player that
I think is a fit that's going to be
there at 21. I mean, Vega Yuane I love
as a player, but I I mean,
>> I would be surprised if he even gets to
18 and and he's a guard and a really
good one. Um,
>> in terms of like some of the other guys,
I I just don't know. I you know I think
versatility is great. I think also
versatility is something we say about
people that we're not sure if they have
a home and and like don't get those
things confused. Like is Kaden Proctor a
tackle who might have to move to guard
or is he just not a very good tackle?
>> I don't know. Yeah.
And I don't want to draft a guy in the
first round that might not be a very
good tackle and I don't have any idea if
he's going to move to guard. I think
we've seen a trend in recent years of
some of these guys that know that
question is coming when they get to the
NFL, they've moved to guard on their own
in in their in college. And I think
that's probably the better way to go for
it. You know, like I said, versatility
is great. If you have It is very rare
though that you have guys that are truly
good at multiple positions. Most of the
time you're either talking about guys
who were just okay at everything or guys
that really just don't have a fit. So,
another I think we can all agree that
they're going to draft a receiver high
and maybe even two of them, you know, in
this draft with all the picks they have.
>> I really think there's about a 0% chance
Tate from Ohio State is there.
>> I think everyone else has I think
everyone else has a chance to be make
21. Do you have a a second favorite? Do
you have a pecking order of the
receivers that you like? Have you ranked
them in any way?
>> I actually think I like Tyson better
than Tate. Do you
>> on tape? It's just the injuries that is
a big factor. You can't really uh you
know it's it's hard to factor what teams
are gonna especially with his because
it's not like he has something that's
ongoing. It's just that he's been hurt
all the time. It's durability and um I
don't know how to weight that. I love
his tape. I think to me he's clearly the
second guy that I would want. But I I
mean I I don't think it's crazy that the
one of those top guys is there for the
Steelers at 21. I think it's very likely
given that they have 12 picks that if
one of those guys even makes it to a
short tradeup range, three, four picks
up that they'll go get them because why
not with 12? I mean, you're not going to
have 12 rookies make the team. No.
>> Do you feel strongly about Boston or
Conception or Lemon or any of those
others? I think Boston for me, I love
him as a player. Uh does feels like the
worst fit for the Steelers. I mean, just
a little too redundant.
>> He is exactly Well, I mean, Mike's just
talking about guys who wanting guys who
can do multiple things. I don't think
he's that. And the one thing he does,
they they already have guys that can do
that. I just think
>> he's
>> the traditional outside the numbers.
>> Yeah. He's he's probably the worst fit.
I think he's a really good player and
and decent chance that he's BPA when
pick 21 comes around. I think I would
rather have if I was like making a big
board sort of for any team, I'd put him
ahead of Conpion and Cooper, but I think
they're better fits for what the
Steelers need right now.
>> Okay.
>> Alan Saunders of Steelers Now with us
here on our little mini radio row at the
league meetings inside the Builtmore. Um
Allan, you know, sticking with that with
that draft conversation, you mentioned
those 12 picks. Is there a sweet spot
for the Steelers to move up? like would
you be interested in maybe nabbing an
additional second round pick? Is there
any thought in your mind even from
potentially moving down to 21 if there's
not the the BPA fit uh that you love as
well?
>> Yeah, I think the the best part of this
draft for me is from about pick
15 to 60. I really like those guys. So
whether it's moving up a little bit in
the first round, um moving up in the
second round, I love the players in the
40 range if they can get into there
>> or moving up to get another second round
pick. I think all those should be on the
table. Those feel like
>> the best ways to use those additional
resources. I'm sure they would also be
interested in trading some of them for
27 capital. Usually you profit on that
exchange by waiting a year,
>> but I think in this situation that's not
going to be the case. Uh talking to
>> you're dumping a late third. You're not
going to get an early second next year.
>> I think every team would like to move
some draft capital from 26 to 27. And
you got to have somebody willing to come
the other way to make it happen. Wes, I
don't think we've talked about this lat
at all, but I think it's more likely
they move from 53 or wherever they pick
in the second up to 40 than they move
from 21 to 17. It'd be a lot less
expensive. You might get your cake and
eat it too with the receiver lineman
situation with a a pick at, you know, 21
and 40 and maybe it only cost you a
fourth or a late third or someone throws
in a fifth next year or whatever. you
know, I just think you could end up with
two guys with similar grades.
>> Yeah, I think that's and the Steelers
have, I would say, been pretty good
under uh Omar Khan at finding those guys
that are falling down the board and and
and getting themselves in position to
meet them where they are. And and I
think that you you know,
>> that's that to me is like his hidden
skill as a general manager. really good
at
>> is that he's very good at understanding
how the rest of the league is going to
value players and and find the the value
picks. And so, yeah, absolutely. They
may not even have to get very far up
from that 53 pick to get a guy that
we're talking about as a borderline
first round player.
>> I could absolutely see that happening
and I've been thinking about it more and
more just the last 48 hours.
>> All right, Allan, we did it. We made it
over 10 minutes into this uh segment
without asking you about Aaron Rogers,
but now geez, now we have to ask you
about Aaron Rogers. Uh any change in uh
what Mike McCarthy had to say this
morning in your mind? Do you still do
you have any timeline on this or is this
just one of those we got to wait and see
and and we won't know until we know?
>> Yeah, I mean I think the Steelers are
pretty clearly planning on him being
their quarterback. I don't think they're
really I mean I'm sure they're doing
some due diligence, but I don't think
they're in any hurry on those other
ideas. I don't think there's anybody
else out there that's worth putting a
hard deadline on for. And really, I
mean, I know that that Art said earlier
this week that, you know, he he expects
to know by the draft. It's not like
they're going to change their draft
plans whether they've already signed
Aaron Rogers or not.
>> They're not going to like Ty Simpson
anymore or less.
>> They're not going up to get Mendoza. No
one other than Mendoza and honestly
maybe not even Mendoza in this draft
class should be playing this year in my
opinion. So like it doesn't like it's
completely separate conversation really
until you start missing OTAA sessions
nothing really matters. So I mean to me
that's the that's the first time that it
becomes an issue.
>> Yeah. And I think I've asked every one
of our guests for the last week or so
this exact same question because I
always preface it the same way. I can
make a really strong case yes or I can
make a really strong case no. the third
to fifth round quarterback pile, the
Becks, the Nusmeers, I mean Aller,
whoever you like.
>> Should you do even bother or are you a
yay or nay on that? Um, well, I think
there are about
maybe three guys that I think are down
there that have traits that are worth
taking a flyer on.
>> I keep going back to Cole Payton. I
think if you don't have upside, it's not
worth just drafting a guy who's probably
a backup. I I would not do that.
>> I agree.
>> I think there are a couple guys
>> That's my problem with Beck.
>> Yeah, I just don't think Beck has the
physical tools. Uh I think Aller does. I
would take him, but maybe not. Like he's
mostly mocked in like the third round.
>> Feels a little rich for me, but I think
he's at least like a gamble worth
taking. Payton is interesting. I'm not
sure he's actually very like I didn't
love him at the Senior Bowl. Thought he
was just okay.
>> He doesn't throw the football great.
>> No. And
uh I think Talon Green is interesting
because just he's such a good athlete
that you know you can run the tush push
with him and you can do some Taesm Hill
stuff with him and maybe it never works
out but if you're talking about a fourth
or fifth round pick and that's all he
becomes like that's not the end of the
world.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But I just like I don't
think they necessarily need like a body.
No,
>> you know,
>> I mean that probably means that Rudolph
gets let go if you do that or in some
way in some
>> I mean like how many of those guys are
going to be better than Mason Rudolph?
Like
>> probably none immediately.
>> Yeah, none immediately and maybe half
ever. Like so
>> to me that's not a
>> I I mean hearing Mike talk I think
they're going to try to draft one but I
seems that way. I don't see that there's
like this pressing like you know I think
my mock drafts I've kind of gone back
and forth where some of them I'll have
one and then some of them I don't.
>> I I I am really exactly on the fence you
know like you might get Dak Prescott or
Perie I mean you might yeah you know but
you have no way knowing but trying but I
can't say I'm doing cartwheels over the
idea either or and that's taken away
from reps that Rudolph's going to or
Howard's going to get. Yeah, but not if
they're just coming at the expense of
Rudolph because, you know, he's probably
going to get reps, too. I don't know. I
think
>> I I think the Howard thing is
interesting. Mike very, you know,
strongly stating his case today for why
he thinks Will Howard has the trades to
be a future starting quarterback. But
also,
>> do you believe that?
>> I mean, I do. Um, you know,
>> seems a little over the top to me. Yeah,
I I believe it because he's given us
some some background at least um for for
why he thinks that now said yesterday,
you know, he gave this long sort of diet
tribe about uh playing in cold weather
and there's certain things that he wants
and he wants size and he wants arm
length and hand size. Oh, Will's hand
size I think is pretty average, but he's
a tall guy. He's a big guy, long arm,
strong, right? Like you can he played in
the cold in college. Uh, and so you can
kind of see him checking those boxes in
the way that that Mike described.
>> So I kind of buy it, but I think there
are also like it's two different it's
it's one thing to say he has starting
quarterback traits. Okay, fine. Like
it's it's also like a 2% chance. Maybe
you want to find out about that 2%
chance. Maybe you're intrigued by it.
But I think they're also realistic
enough that hey, take take another shot
if you can. Like it's not it's not like
this is some kind of sure thing. Mhm.
That's an interesting conversation.
>> Allan, last one I've got for you is uh
Mike McCarthy kind of saying the right
things and and in positive conversation
about Caleb Williams or Caleb Williams,
pardon me, Caleb Johnson and Roman
Wilson. Uh which of those two do you
think has the better shot to carve out a
role under this new regime?
>> That's a tough way to phrase that. I'm
not overly bullish on either of their
chances as we sit here right now. I
think I mean Caleb just feels very boxed
out of reps. Like I I don't know where
the opportunity comes. He pretty much
needs somebody to get hurt at this
point.
>> And I think
>> there's at least more roster spots at
the receiver position.
>> And I think he will run the ball very
very well when he finally gets an
opportunity to do so. I have never had a
doubt about Caleb Johnson's ability as a
ball carrier. Pass protection, route
running, his hands. I I have questions.
Obviously, special teams didn't go great
last year, but I think if if they needed
him, somebody gets hurt and they need
him to go have, you know, five to 10
carries a game, I think he could be very
good in that role. Uh Roman Wilson, I I
don't think is a very good fit for this
offense. Uh he doesn't really do those
multiple things that Mike McCarthy was
talking about. I think he would best be
pigeonholed as a slot receiver
somewhere. And I think his traits that
he brought to the table, the things you
saw at Michigan that made him the draft
pick that he became is toughness,
physicality, run blocking, ability, a
willingness to go over the middle, but
he is not this sort of precise route
runner technician that you associate
with a West Coast offense slot receiver.
So, I think this scheme is going to be a
worse fit for him. But I do think there
is always a a sort of and Mike had a
great quote about it. You know, it's he
said it's the Catholic operation. Say
three Hail Marys and the priest absolves
you and
>> your slate is clean.
>> Yeah. And you get a clean slate. It's
like I I think that's true, but like I I
don't I don't know where the role comes
from for either of those guys really. I
think Roman has a bigger opportunity.
Obviously, there's just much less depth
at wide receiver.
>> I have one last thing for you. Like I'm
going to assume, especially with the
number of picks they have, they're going
to draft at least one defensive back of
some shape, size, or whatever. Free
safety, strong safety, nickel, big corn,
you know, outside guy, nick, small
nickel, big nickel, whatever. What style
do you think they're looking for first
and foremost to add to the secondary?
>> I really don't know. I mean, I think
that
>> a lot of this is what do you do with
Ramsey?
>> I think the signing of Jamal Dean tells
me that they want to play manto man.
They want to have the ability to play
man-to-man
>> with size.
>> And I think they probably don't have
anyone certainly don't have anyone long
term and I don't even know if they have
anyone in short term that you can say
okay go in the slot and cover Z Flowers
manto man. To me that's the thing
they're lacking. I also think it's a
really good slot corner draft. Yeah.
>> I really like the day two guys that are
slot corners. And so to me that feels
like the biggest thing that they don't
have that will be
>> and then you think say Ramsay becomes
more safety first.
>> Well I just think for this year it could
be a small role. It could just be hey
you're the nickel when we're playing
Baltimore because it's Zay Flowers and
then when you go play
>> Patrick Graham is very weak to
>> and when you go play somebody else who
plays all 12 personnel and it's a 6'5
tight end in there. Okay then maybe it
needs to be forget Ramsay maybe it needs
to be Deshawn Elliott whatever you know.
Uh but Right. Yeah.
>> It would be a it could be a small part
at first and then you see how things go
and then hey, if it's a young guy who's
who looks like he's deserving more
playing time, then sure, you can let
Brisker walk away and you could move
Ramsay to safety full time. But I think
that's an area where that's the one
thing in the secondary I really don't
think they have where you feel really
good about okay like manto man in this
situation. They they kind of have all
the other boxes checked.
>> Great stuff with our buddy Allan
Saunders. Just make sure you're checking
out all his coverage this week and
always steelers.com. Thanks for taking
the time, dude. Appreciate it.
>> Thanks, Phil.
>> Don't uh don't melt too much out there
on us now. All right,
>> I'll try.
>> You're tuned to the drive on your 247
home of the black and gold Steelers
Nation Radio.